<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NEH | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/neh/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/neh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>NEH</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 23:45:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>NEH</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/neh/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants being aggregated in OLAC Search results</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/olac-grant-aggregator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 23:45:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/olac-grant-aggregator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been doing some thinking about what would make 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://search.language-archives.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OLAC search&lt;/a&gt; more valuable to its current users and to its targeted users. One of the things which would make it more useful would be if the NSF, a partial funder for 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.language-archives.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OLAC&lt;/a&gt; and OLAC search, would aggregate its language related grants, scholarships, fellowships and awards through OLAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these Grant proposals are really well written, and well cited documents which explain a certain snapshot of the language situation. Even the announcements that a grants like 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward.do?AwardNumber=0966411&amp;amp;WT.z_pims_id=12816&#34; title=&#34;Douglas Whalen Grant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;From Endangered Language Documentation to Phonetic Documentation&lt;/a&gt; has been awarded would allow other researchers to know that someone has applied or been awarded a block of funding to work on a particular language situation.&lt;/p&gt;



  
  
  

&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-notice-of-nsf-grant-award&#34;itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/olac-grant-aggregator/NSF-Grant_hue2c2cdacdb65db441481dd609fada4c1_318924_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Notice of NSF Grant award&#34;&gt;

  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/olac-grant-aggregator/NSF-Grant_hue2c2cdacdb65db441481dd609fada4c1_318924_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;Notice of NSF Grant award&#34; width=&#34;1436&#34; height=&#34;881&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Notice of NSF Grant award
      
&lt;span class=&#34;img-attribution&#34;&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward.do?AwardNumber=0966411&amp;amp;WT.z_pims_id=12816&#34;&gt; NSF&lt;span itemprop=&#34;creator&#34; itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34; itemscope&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;name&#34; content=&#34;NSF&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was particularly happy to find that NSF does have a &lt;em&gt;grant offering&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;grant awarded&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/progSearch.do?WT.si_n=ClickedAbstractsRecentAwards&amp;amp;WT.si_x=1&amp;amp;WT.si_cs=1&amp;amp;WT.z_pims_id=12816&amp;amp;SearchType=progSearch&amp;amp;page=2&amp;amp;QueryText=&amp;amp;ProgOrganization=&amp;amp;ProgOfficer=&amp;amp;ProgEleCode=7719&amp;amp;BooleanElement=true&amp;amp;ProgRefCode=&amp;amp;BooleanRef=true&amp;amp;ProgProgram=&amp;amp;ProgFoaCode=&amp;amp;RestrictActive=on&amp;amp;Search=Search#results&#34; title=&#34;NSF Grants&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;search section&lt;/a&gt;. But aggregating this knowledge with prior research would really give interested parties in particular languages the integrated perspective of how funding has impacted the development and research of minority languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I supported and conducted field work in this multi-scholar collaboration documenting the various speech varieties of the Meꞌphaa Genius. The protagonist in this effort was Dr. Steven Marlett. He applied for and was awarded&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; a DEL-NEH fellowship and invited Kevin and me to work on our own, but adjacent projects at the same place and time as he was working on his project. Contextually this was a very interesting project and formative in my scholarly experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My major contribution to the research project(s) was three fold: First, I provided audio and video recording technical expertise for the recording of communicative events. Second, I provided file organization and metadata support for all the scholars involved. Third, I helped design and implement the elicitation of social and biographical information for the people who worked with us, so that we could better understand the social dynamics behind the spoken variation we encountered. Contextually this role was very interesting because I functioned as a &lt;em&gt;field archivist&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;multi-media recording technician&lt;/em&gt; working with linguists, yet I also contributed to the overall design of the information collected. This pairing of activites and conceptializing in a single role was not easily articulated at the time, even by me. Commonly understood roles of the time were &lt;em&gt;IT Support&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;linguist&lt;/em&gt;; I fit neither of these pre-concived roles 100%. Therefore, I sometimes say that &amp;ldquo;being a grammarian of digital file names is the loneliest job of them all&amp;rdquo;. However, if social expectations among team members can be well established, the inclusion of a &lt;em&gt;field archivist&lt;/em&gt; on an interdisciplinary linguistic team can provide significant advantages to information managment and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;File-man.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;File Grammarian&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;story_recording_in_mexico_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hugh Recording&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Dr. Steven Marlett&amp;rsquo;s Fellowship lasted 12 months, my own involvement consisted of two discontinuous three-month stents. Many of the lessons learned and reflections on our project are recorded in short (or longer) blog posts. Significant though are that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.und.edu/theses/1410&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kevin Cline used this time to gather data his Masters Thesis&lt;/a&gt;, Dr. Marlett would use the knowledge and relationships to write a massive amount of descriptive material and texts on and in the Meꞌphaa speech varieties. These are known as the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mexico.sil.org/publications/i-wpindex/work_papers_-_mephaa_grammar_files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meꞌphaa Grammar Files&lt;/a&gt; and are published under the SIL Mexico Working Papers series. My own scholarly contribution informed by and influenced through this project would span multiple topics but would include the areas of text input, metadata schemas, project managment, and geo-linguistics (language maps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20111110085938/http://www.neh.gov/grants/guidelines/pdf/DEL_NEH_Marlett.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marlett Fellowship Narrative&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- http://www.neh.gov/grants/guidelines/pdf/DEL_NEH_Marlett.pdf --&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
