<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Hugh&#39;s Resume</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Hugh&#39;s Resume</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hugh Paterson III &amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Code Serving Endangered Languages</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2016-open-source-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2016-open-source-code/</guid>
      <description>Citable as:
Richard Littauer, Hugh Paterson III (2016) Open Source Code Serving Endangered Languages. In: C. Soria, L. Pretorius, T. Declerck, J. Mariani, K. Scannell, Eveline Wandl-Vogt, eds., In Proceedings of LREC 2016 Collaboration and Computing for Under-Resourced Languages: Towards an Alliance for Digital Language Diversity (CCURL) Workshop. Portorož, Slovenia, 23 May, 2016. pp. 86-88.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-tone-transcription/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-tone-transcription/</guid>
      <description>This was a poster presentation presented at the 18th International Conference of Phonetic Sciences in 2015. Links are to the poster and the 5 page paper is in the conference proceedings.
Citeable as:
Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA. In The Scottish Consortium for ICPhS 2015 (Ed.). Proceedings of the 18th International Conference of Phonetic Sciences Paper number 507.1-5. University of Glasgow: Glasgow, UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lexical dataset archiving: an assessment of practice</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-lexical-database-archiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-lexical-database-archiving/</guid>
      <description>Citeable as:
Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) Lexical dataset archiving: an assessment of practice. Poster presented at the 4th International Conference on Language Documentation and Conservation, at the Ala Moana Hotel in Honolulu, HI. February 26th – March 1st Version 1.0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard layouts: Lessons from the Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec designs</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2014-keyboard-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2014-keyboard-layouts/</guid>
      <description>Citeable as:
Hugh J. Paterson III (2014) Keyboard layouts: Lessons from the Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec designs. In: Endangered Languages and New Technologies edited by Mari C. Jones. pp. 49-66. Cambridge University Press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges of implementing a tool to extract metadata from linguists: the use case of RAMP</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2013-challenges-ramp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 07:18:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2013-challenges-ramp/</guid>
      <description>Citeable as:
Hugh J. Paterson III and Jeremy Nordmoe (2013) Challenges of implementing a tool to extract metadata from linguists: the use case of RAMP. Poster presented at 3rd International Conference on Language Documentation and Conservation, at the University of Hawai&amp;rsquo;i Mānoa, Honolulu, HI. February 28 - March 3rd. 
Bibliography for Poster:  Anderson, Stephen P. 2006. Creating Pleasurable interfaces: Getting from Tasks to Experiences (Poster). http://www.artificialindustry.com/uploads/inspiratie/1295515106from-task-to-experience.png  Anderson, Stephen P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Las Conexiones Externas e Internas</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2011-mexico-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 20:21:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2011-mexico-places/</guid>
      <description>Citeable as:
Kevin L. Cline, Stephen A. Marlett, Hugh Paterson III and Mark L. Weathers. (November 2011) Las Conexiones Externas e Internas. En: Stephen A. Marlett (ed.) Los Archivos Lingüísticos Me&amp;rsquo;phaa. [http://www.sil.org/mexico/workpapers/WP013-PDF/MephaaConexiones.pdf]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The phonetic status of the (inter)dental approximant.</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2010-interdental/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.github.io/Hugh-CV/publication/2010-interdental/</guid>
      <description>Citeable as:
Kenneth S. Olson, Jeff Mielke, Josephine Sanicas-Daguman, Carol Jean Pebley and Hugh J. Paterson (2010) The phonetic status of the (inter)dental approximant. Journal of the International Phonetic Association, 40 , pp. 199-215. doi:10.1017/S0025100309990296
Comments: My contribution in this collective work involved extensive library research, the collection of sources, translation of sources, and evaluating the personal un-published field notes of previous scholars. Encouraged in the historical comparative work by Ken Olson, I suggest that there is enough evidence to support the idea that the interdental approximant is a retention, rather than independent innovations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>