<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dallas | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/cities/dallas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/cities/dallas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Dallas</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Dallas</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/cities/dallas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Experience Consulting on SIL.org</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within User Experience studies, there are at least two ways to apply the term (UX): &lt;em&gt;The design of experiences that a corporation wants their customers to engage in&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;the  way that people take an object (product) and decide to use it&lt;/em&gt;. Both are important, but how a company approaches either of these facets and how they relate that approach back to their other business goals scopes the relevance of User Experience Design within the organization. Successful interactions depend on both points of view and the metrics chosen for evaluating success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 2010 and 2016 I intergrated with the SIL communications team to contribute to desin descussions on the SIL website. The project was to move the current website from hand crafted HTML poduced by dozens of departments over hundreds of projects to Drupal 7, a content manament system. The move to a content managment system was a strategic move for the organization that impacted all parts of the organization. I contributed a variety of perspectives to an evolving design incuding &lt;em&gt;Readability&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Professional profile design&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;URL managment&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;SEO considerations&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Interactive features&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;List layout and design&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Page element cohesion&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Designing for web and print&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Multi-lingual navigation&lt;/em&gt;, .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I raised empathy considerations, where the tasks of the end-user were considered over the traditions of the organization. I brought an awareness of what other organizations in the pulishing industry were doing and their users were expecting from a web-based interaction. I was able to be a resource introducing some of these design ideas to a communications team with diverse strenghts in print design and text based messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;ndash; My work with SIL started with a report that they were not using a &lt;code&gt;print.css&lt;/code&gt; file on the SIL Bibliography in 2006 and were wasting a lot of ink when people were printing pages. I think this was corrected by 2009. This was typical for the pace of technical innovative change. SIL is a very corporate feature focused development environment.
&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL.org is an interesting use case in UX design for at least 6 reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL has several major areas of very public interactions which it engages with to various degrees in various parts of the world — but the Internet is flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocacy with public policy making bodies regarding the needs of minority language speakers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing and sales of professional resources and materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bible translation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Educational programs (both formal and workshop style) in linguistics and language development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mother tongue Multi-lingual educational programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minority language literacy (both integrated with national educational programs, and community sponsored programs, for children and adults).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NGOs and development agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative computer technology development related to non-English typesetting and computing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative creative access power solutions (like solar).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainable logistical support for difficult to access project locations (usually via air).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL has historically had a very fractured internal identity, and a very decentralized governance, which has not required a high degree of uniformity throughout the organization. Digital infrastructure projects stress these social norms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the organization web-presence has come to be regarded as the officiating act recognition of an internal group&amp;rsquo;s merit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different people within the organization have strong opinions about how the world should view the organization — which are reflected in what they think the organization should say about itself — including the interactions that the organization provides to the people who interact via its website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally at the time the Internet was going mobile mobile-first, something not until-then  considered in web-designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL had, and conintues to have, multiple audiences for which the organization has very different engagement goals. For example, generating the visual and informatic thrill needed to entice donors is a different communication task than facilitating product (publication and product) distribution. These tasks and their audiences are then again different from training and education related interactions for which SIL was offereing. SIL also provides high-level information about subject areas in which SIL engages  focused at politicians and staffs of other NGOs. However, quantitatively, most people came to SIL.org to learn about linguistics, the plethora of digital tools that SIL distributes via sil.org, or the vast number of resources about languages and the people who speak them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;!--
Rebranding SIL Journals

Journal of phonological description
Journal of grammatical description
Journal of descriptive and comparative dialectology
Journal of orthographic description and history
Journal of sociolinguistic description
--&gt;
&lt;!--  8 May 2013-  I sometimes wonder if Vision2025 applied to sil.org is to shut the website down and turn it off. If every language which needs a Bible Translation will have a project started by 2025. Then there really is no place left for SIL after that and why would SIL need a website then?

:: because we all believe that Bible Translation is more important than Language Development and there will be no way to share what Christ did for us in humanity after 2025 through language development.

:: because we all know that there will be no need for Bible Translation Revisions, after 2025... We got it right the first time...

:: because SIL will have spent all its time and effort preaching to partners &#34;sustainability&#34; it will have none in the end...

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OWL and the Rice Farmer</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-owl-and-the-rice-farmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 14:14:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-owl-and-the-rice-farmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent email I was asked by a &lt;em&gt;European Linguistic Professional SIL Colleague&lt;/em&gt; about the ease of use of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.mpi.nl/tla/elan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELAN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is ELAN easy enough to use, so that an Indonesian rice farmer can use it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am offended with the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; terminology which is prevalent in SIL discourse. However, to understand this term, and its usage I think it is important to understand another term used prior to &lt;em&gt;the rice farmer&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;em&gt;The Ordinary Working Linguist&lt;/em&gt;. This older phrase has gained some traction as evidenced by its adoption in the linguistic literature&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OWL&lt;/em&gt; or &amp;lsquo;ordinary working linguist&amp;rsquo; is attributed 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icsi.berkeley.edu/icsi/blog/chuck-fillmore-dies-at-84&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;by George Lakoff&lt;/a&gt; to Charles Fillmore as a self-describing term. Though it is impossible to say if Fillmore actually coined the term. If he did, then it is an interesting frame by the discoverer of cognitive framing. I have yet to meet an &lt;em&gt;ordinary linguist&lt;/em&gt;. I have met smart linguists, extraordinary linguists, novel linguists, quirky linguists, geeky linguists, and ornery linguists — but never an &lt;em&gt;ordinary one&lt;/em&gt;. The second issue I take with this contrived frame is that it suggests that somewhere there might be a &lt;em&gt;non-working linguist&lt;/em&gt;. Now, either I have never met a lazy linguist, or I have been foiled by some collective endeavor. That is, the linguists I have met have somehow &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; decided that I am an extremely boring person — the kind to be avoided, and &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; have feigned busyness! Granted busyness is not the same as &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo;, but I have never met a linguist who is not engaged in some sort of activity which has a mistakable similitude to &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the same, the notion of &amp;ldquo;OWL&amp;rdquo; seems to be very useful to a large group of linguists. For instance, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholars.sil.org/gary_f_simons/preprint/computing_environment&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gary F. Simons suggests&lt;/a&gt; that Helen Aristar Dry proposed a book in the early 1990s with the title &lt;em&gt;Computers and the Ordinary Working Linguist.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, While David Nathan, Peter Austin, Andrew Black, Piotr Bański, Mike Cahill, Jeff Good, Steven Moran, Scott Farrar, and René van den Berg all use the term in their works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In honor of Fillmore, if we take a framing view of the phrase &amp;ldquo;ordinary working linguist&amp;rdquo; we can see that many of the authors are discussing the concept within the frame of linguistic computing — the computer tools that linguists use to do their work. However, it can be argued that there is an SIL specific shift in the framing of the phrase (usage by Cahill, Schroeder, Simons, Black, and van den Berg). Van den Berg&amp;rsquo;s use is most articulate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the typical SIL fieldworker is what has been called an ‘owl’, that is, an ‘ordinary working linguist’ who has been given enough training to enable him or her to do the job; this  is usually a minimum of  two semesters of field linguistics at graduate level. A typical SIL field worker is therefore very  much a generalist, without specialist knowledge in any branch of linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van den Berg&amp;rsquo;s usage is both confirmed and then contrasted by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20130308204655/https://www.sil.org/linguistics/people&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIL International&lt;/a&gt; on its website where it contrasts the term with &lt;em&gt;Linguistics Coordinators&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Linguistics Consultants&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;International Linguistics Advisors&lt;/em&gt;. It is clear to see that within the shared frame by SIL staff, that Linguistic Consultants are those who have more training than typical SIL field workers. For several reasons, including reduced staffing, and paradigm shifts within project management related moral ownership within the tasks of language development, SIL has moved from ex-pat driven projects to nationally staffed and ethnolinguistic community driven projects. SIL&amp;rsquo;s minimally trained &amp;ldquo;OWLs&amp;rdquo; moved up the organizational chart to become project managers/facilitators, leaving open the &amp;ldquo;bottom&amp;rdquo; of the chart, ergo the new need for &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; as a newly perceived class of computer user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the term &lt;em&gt;rice farmer&lt;/em&gt; 14 times in the internal SIL International wiki and I find &amp;ldquo;OWL&amp;rdquo; 83 times. These terms surface mostly among SIL computer app developers, but I also hear them used by SIL policy and procedures developers, SIL program planners, and SIL educators. To me this term comes off as a class distinction term (and maybe there is nothing wrong with class distinction; I mean the Jews had class distinctions at the time of Jesus, the Cretans had classes at the time of Titus, the British have it, and castes are alive and well in India, etc.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). However, as I find the term being used in SIL, a more transparent term might be &amp;lsquo;low socio-economic and low educational &lt;em&gt;capacity&lt;/em&gt; individual&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that in my work with Steve Marlett in Mexico, I worked with ethnolinguistic moronity language users who were not &amp;lsquo;low educational capacity individuals&amp;rsquo; rather they were high educational capacity individuals. When I went to Malaysia and worked with Sean Conklin, the same thing, ethnolinguistic minority language users were not low educational capacity individuals. When I went to Nigeria and worked with people like Becky Paterson and David Rowbory, the people doing language work with us were not low educational capacity individuals. In fact the Nigerian rice farmer/pastor/student/translator/cultural guide/language activist who was on our language project team can and does use ELAN after some training (and uses Facebook without training to boot — FYI: I need training on ELAN too!). So, why then do SIL staff use terms like &amp;lsquo;rice farmers&amp;rsquo; when they talk about designing software for users? Something seems to be wrong with this picture. My guess is that there is a real reason why SIL staff use the term, but it is not the reason that SIL staff attribute as the causation of the observation of &amp;ldquo;low educational capacity individuals&amp;rdquo; - as we observe dark skinned colleagues who try and use SIL software and don&amp;rsquo;t intuitively know how to use the tools. My guess is that the reason for the use of the term is because it is part of the SIL corporate ethos. SIL staff use (or at least have in the past) their educational courses at various SIL training events as filters to find the &amp;lsquo;best and brightest students&amp;rsquo; and recommend those for various field service within SIL. Then in the advanced classes SIL staff obfuscate the materials just to make them harder, to see if those same students are able to still keep up. So, as I see it, there seems to be this undefined class difference in SIL&amp;rsquo;s corporate sociology preferring those who can distill obfuscated communications under stress and dis-preferring those who cannot distill obfuscated signals under stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the following four reasons I strongly dis-prefer the terms &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;OWL&amp;rsquo; as they often appear in SIL discourse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; terminology is actually very useful for professional reasons. Software design is about communicating. It is about communicating relational concepts in a visual context. It is about connecting new analogies with salient concepts. User Interface (UI - what a software user sees and interacts with) is the gateway to User Experience (UX - the emotional, logical, task based context of activities that are attempting to be facilitated by the software designer and accomplished by the software user). Therefore what UX is really about is communicating ideas and creating positive and successful interactions. If the UI fails to create the designed UX then it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the user is a rice farmer or a Ph.D. candidate from an Australian university. The end result is that the user is frustrated and will not use the software willingly. Therefore, singling out the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; from the white guy is not really a useful construct because all users, whether black, white, tan, farmer, or stockbroker, are subject to the same constraints and frustrations of software which is not intuitively implemented. It is my experience that programmers (not just SIL programmers) usually do not intuitively know how application users think or behave. UX design is an art and a science that takes experimentation and a solid grasp of information design principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget that, at least in software design we are talking about the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; with a computer, an iPad, or an android device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We never use the American Corn Farmer, or the Norwegian Reindeer Rancher as analogies, and I am a bit tired of singling out people from tropical areas because their skin is darker, or their average height is shorter, or because they grow rice in their backyard. The focus on the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; does not help us deal with the white guy&amp;rsquo;s problem with the software and robs us of a balanced view of the real communication challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the term &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; seems to put the ethnolinguistic minority language users and nationals in a sub-standard class relative to &amp;lsquo;real linguists&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;real missionaries&amp;rsquo;. Yes, my African colleagues who do have their own farms and families, also use SIL software; I first drove a tractor at age 13 and grew up on a farm, so what is the difference? By making the &amp;lsquo;OWL&amp;rsquo; or the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; as some uninitiated or limited capacity person,  the &amp;ldquo;reason&amp;rdquo; for new design (i.e the reason that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://software.sil.org/wesay&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WeSay&lt;/a&gt; was created to work with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://software.sil.org/fieldworks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FLEx&lt;/a&gt;) doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve the fact that even for highly-educated-white-professionals FLEx is still confusing. The issue is a visual communications issue not a smarts or intelligence issue. Linguistic concepts can be communicated about beautifully and communicated simply, both in the classroom and in software. &lt;!-- also note the framing that John Hatton has taken about PhD in having training for software but nations don&#39;t in his presentation  on SayMore here: https://scholarspace.manoa.hawaii.edu/handle/10125/26153?mode=full --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this post motivates those in SIL to take a deeper look at User Experience issues in the software tools and websites we build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- also uses the term 
1. https://tel.archives-ouvertes.fr/tel-03131936/document 
2. https://doi.org/10.1515/ling-2017-0032 Reproducible research in linguistics:
A position statement on data citation and attribution in our field. 
3. https://doi.org/10.1515/lity.2002.007 Recent activity in the theory of aspect: Accomplishments, achievements, or just non-progressive state?
4. https://doi.org/10.1075/cilt.32.10lon Robert Longachre in New Directions in Linguistics and Semiotics  
5. Fellow essay: https://www.essaysinlinguistics.com/2018/09/12/fillmore/--&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bański, Piotr. 2010. Why TEI stand-off annotation doesn’t quite work: and why you might want to use it nevertheless. In Proceedings of Balisage: The Markup Conference 2010 (Balisage Series on Markup Technologies 5), n.p. Montréal, Canada: Balisage. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4242/BalisageVol5.Banski01&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4242/BalisageVol5.Banski01&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;van den Berg, René. 2013. SIL and its contribution to Oceanic linguistics. Language and Linguistics in Oceania 5. 33–74. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.izumi-syuppan.co.jp/LLO_PDF/vol_05/13Berg.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.izumi-syuppan.co.jp/LLO_PDF/vol_05/13Berg.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black, H Andrew &amp;amp; Gary F Simons. 2008. The SIL Fieldworks Language Explorer Approach to Morphological Parsing. In Nick Gaylord, Alexis Palmer &amp;amp; Elias Ponvert (eds.), Texas Linguistics Society 10: Computational Linguistics for Less-Studied Languages, 37–55. Stanford, California: CSLI Publications. &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.stanford.edu/group/cslipublications/cslipublications/TLS/TLS10-2006/TLSX-2006-toc.shtml&#34;&gt;http://web.stanford.edu/group/cslipublications/cslipublications/TLS/TLS10-2006/TLSX-2006-toc.shtml&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cahill, Mike C. 2001. Farewell from the Coordinator. Notes on Linguistics 4(4). 203–204. &lt;a href=&#34;https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED467733.pdf&#34;&gt;https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED467733.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farrar, Scott &amp;amp; Steven Moran. 2008. The e-Linguistics toolkit. In Workshop in the 4th IEEE International Conference on e-Science, Indianapolis, Indiana, 10 December 2008, n.p. IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5167/UZH-84686&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5167/UZH-84686&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good, Jeff. 2010. Valuing technology: Finding the linguist’s place in a new technological universe. In Lenore A. Grenoble &amp;amp; N. Louanna Furbee (eds.), Language Documentation: Practice and values, 111–132. Amsterdam: John Benjamins Publishing Company. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/z.158.13goo&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/z.158.13goo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan, David &amp;amp; Peter K Austin. 2004. Reconceiving metadata: language documentation through thick and thin. Language Documentation and Description 2. 179–188. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/029&#34;&gt;http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/029&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schroeder, Leila. 2008. Bantu Orthography Manual (SIL E-Books 9). Revised 2010. Dallas, Texas: SIL International. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sil.org/resources/archives/9241&#34;&gt;https://www.sil.org/resources/archives/9241&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which would be later published as: Aristar Dry, Helen &amp;amp; John Lawler (eds.). 1998. Using Computers in Linguistics: A Practical Guide. 1st edn. London: Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203059012&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203059012&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States doesn&amp;rsquo;t have classes, only more successful capitalists and less successful capitalists. — ⟨snark⟩ &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Resource Metadata for Linguistic &amp; Language Resources</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-lrmi-metadata-for-linguistic-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-lrmi-metadata-for-linguistic-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is more like a research theme. It started with some felt needs in the SIL International Training Department where I was working. We were seeking to better automate and craft the SIL course catalogue, professional development plans, and course content, while providing instructors clear access to known resources they could use in their learning events. This work involved conceptualizing the course catalogue from both the training and human resources points of view along with supporting resources. SIL&amp;rsquo;s training events are SIL licensed or implemented under contract at partner institutions of higher education. Often the contracted instruction is done via independent-ish SIL branded organizations often refereed to as &lt;em&gt;SIL Entities&lt;/em&gt; e.g., SIL Peru, SIL Philippines, etc. Entities are often a geographical locus of operations and work out their own partnerships and resource management strategies. The SIL Language &amp;amp; Culture Archive maintains specific collections for each SIL entity, one of those collections is usually for training resources. Connecting these resources to competencies is important for understanding the use, value, and re-use capability of the resource. I started looking out at how this connection between resource and competency was solved in the larger professional space. In the process I was introduced to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning_Resource_Metadata_Initiative&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Learning Resource Metadata Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (LRMI) and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning_object_metadata&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Learning Object Metadata&lt;/a&gt; (LOM) communities. My work in this capacity resulted in a recommendation to SIL to integrate LRMI into the archive for instructional materials dealing with linguistics along with mother-tongue based literacy materials. SIL choose that this was not a corporate priority. However, in the process I realized that the language revitalization community at large also has the same challenges. This project page serves to pull together my actions across these contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-audio-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-audio-digitization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project involved the accession, cataloging and digitization of several collections. It also involved cataloging of multiple collections already accessioned but not yet cataloged. I was responsible for identifying and collecting metadata relevant for audio collections. I communicated with the SIL Language and Culture Archive staff when metadata schemas in place were insufficient for audio collections. I identified and recommended changes to metadata profiles used at the time by the Language and Culture Archives. I consulted industry best practices and established quality control procedures related to the digitization of cassette tapes and reel to reel tapes. I served as project manager, with a volunteer workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-photo-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-photo-digitization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I served as project manager, recruiting and supervising a volunteer workforce. Together we cataloged and scanned over 1000 photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also repatriated some photos. We took old photo albums to reunions where former SIL staff identified persons and places in the images.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-text-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-text-digitization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked with the SIL Americas Area Access Coordinator to make language materials available to translators, researchers, and language development workers. There is a wealth of information that is simply inaccessible to those who could use it. I helped in the implementation of a system to make these materials available digitally, via the internet. Access to these materials affects the mechanics of language development and translation projects throughout the Americas Area and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contributed in general to archiving processes related to text scanning, and the post processing of these scans into archival and distribution formats. I served as site manager and recruiter with a volunteer work force. I brokered accessions of older materials from their creators.
I worked with IT staff to produce an automated reporting mechanism to track team progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
-- insert photos
-- insert data progress chart --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
