<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SIL Mexico | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/sil-mexico/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/sil-mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>SIL Mexico</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>SIL Mexico</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/sil-mexico/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I supported and conducted field work in this multi-scholar collaboration documenting the various speech varieties of the Meꞌphaa Genius. The protagonist in this effort was Dr. Steven Marlett. He applied for and was awarded&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; a DEL-NEH fellowship and invited Kevin and me to work on our own, but adjacent projects at the same place and time as he was working on his project. Contextually this was a very interesting project and formative in my scholarly experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My major contribution to the research project(s) was two fold: First, I provided audio and video recording technical expertise for the recording of communicative events; second, I provided file organization and metadata support for all the scholars involved. Contextually this role was very interesting because I functioned as a field archivist and multi-media recording technician working with linguists. This pairing was not well understood at the time, even by me. Commonly understood roles were &lt;em&gt;IT Support&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;linguist&lt;/em&gt;; I fit neither 100%. Therefore, I sometimes say that &amp;ldquo;being a grammarian of digital file names is the loneliest job of them all&amp;rdquo;. However, if social expectations among team members can be well established, including a &lt;em&gt;field archivist&lt;/em&gt; on an interdisciplinary linguistic team can provide significant advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Dr. Steven Marlett&amp;rsquo;s Fellowship lasted 12 months, my own involvement consisted of two discontinuous three-month stents. Many of the lessons learned and reflections on our project are recorded in short (or longer) blog posts. Significant though are that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.und.edu/theses/1410&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kevin Cline used this time to gather data his Masters Thesis&lt;/a&gt;, Dr. Marlett would use the knowledge and relationships to write a massive amount of descriptive material and texts on and in the Meꞌphaa speech varieties. These are known as the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mexico.sil.org/publications/i-wpindex/work_papers_-_mephaa_grammar_files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meꞌphaa Grammar Files&lt;/a&gt; and are published under the SIL Mexico Working Papers series. My own scholarly contribution informed by and influenced through this project would span multiple topics but would include the areas of text input, metadata schemas, project managment, and geo-linguistics (language maps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;File-man.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hugh in recording&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20111110085938/http://www.neh.gov/grants/guidelines/pdf/DEL_NEH_Marlett.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marlett Fellowship Narrative&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- http://www.neh.gov/grants/guidelines/pdf/DEL_NEH_Marlett.pdf --&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
