<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae on Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae on Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hugh Paterson III &amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/Hugh-CV/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>TEI Lexicon Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/tei-lexicon-bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 14:35:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/tei-lexicon-bibliography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short non-exhaustive bibliography of lexicon projects which have tested or opted to use the XML TEI format for their data.

Citations are kept in a GitHub gist. Comments are welcome via GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;//gist.github.com/HughP/3b3faf1f2a8a579b91a46a2f1d6ceaa1.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard layouts across languages: A Text input analysis</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2018-thesis-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2018-thesis-proposal/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposal&#34;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital language death is a real issue for many small and under-resourced languages. To use Kornai’s (2013) terms, the digital moribund state of languages is accelerated by the lack of intuitive and useful text input methods for many minority and under-resourced languages. Even if text input methods currently exist for a language, it is often the case that they are disruptive (rather than smooth) to the digital text production process, due to inadequately optimized keyboards. This disruption then serves as a barrier to creating vibrant digital communities using these under-resourced languages. What is observed is that users of under-resourced languages often choose to use another language in digital contexts rather than deal with the disruptions of awkward keyboard input requirements. This actually serves to accelerate and solidify the under-resourced language in its moribund “vitality” state.
Optimized Keyboard Layouts are an academic pursuit in applied mathematics and computer science which intend to make keyboards intuitive and useful. Despite being language-related resources, keyboards and text input methods are rarely mentioned in the language development literature.
Within the computer science literature Yin and Su (2011) situate the optimization of the keyboard in a context known as the general keyboard arrangement problem (GKAP). Their work is well respected, but does not take into account several issues common to the minority-language context, such as keyboards with deadkey interactions, graphemic complexities (such as diacritic usage), and embedded linguistic knowledge (such as tone patterns, or multi-graph functional units). For example, Bi et al. (2012) look at the efficiency of text input with the deadkey method for diacritics, and contrast that with a single keystroke for a “composed” character. They conclude that the deadkey method is more efficient, but they only run their tests on European languages with orthographies that have a diacritic to total character density of less than 4%. Commonly, European languages use diacritics to indicate vowel quality. In contrast, many languages use diacritics to show tone patterns. In preliminary counts of minority-languages in both Mexico and Nigeria, I have encountered diacritic densities of over 30%. This means the extra time and effort it takes to use deadkeys is much more significant in these languages.
Paterson (2014) lays a foundation for the kinds of issues encountered by minority-languages typists, as an appeal to creators of resources for under-resourced languages to use design principles (Vitsœ 2012, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services 2018) in the creation of their language resource products. There, I argue that better design of text input solutions, which take into account linguistic knowledge about a language’s orthography, will increase the opportunities for digital vitality in an under-resourced language.  It does not, however, present a methodology for assessing the disruptive nature of a text input solution, so we still lack a metric for comparing the relative ease of typing on any given keyboard layout for a given language.
There currently does not exist a principled way to evaluate the utility or the application of User Experience principles (Garrett 2002) and design criteria to keyboard layouts. Researchers who have published on the keyboard optimization problem generally evaluate keyboard layouts on the basis of a composite “fitness score”. These scores only take into account the metrics of a single language - generally English - and only do it from an ergonomic perspective. As researchers in the field of language development, we are effectively blind when it comes to our ability to compare efficiency of two proposed keyboard layouts serving the same language,. A good framework does not exist for allowing researchers to ask the question: does QWERTY serve English users equally as well as AWERZY does to French users? - or any number of keyboards and their corresponding minority-languages.
Language development practitioners and linguists working in many different languages have created many keyboard layouts.  However, linguists have not adequately accounted for the linguistic dissonance between the psycholinguistic and phonemic realities of a spoken language and a speaker’s experience in typing that language. This has created a gap between the “possible to write/type” orthography and the “easy to write/type” orthography.
The general keyboard arrangement problem (GKAP) has been situated as a time over distance problem, i.e., speed. The assumption has been that if fingers travel a smaller distance, then faster typing should be the result. A secondary argument to increase speed has been to reduce effort. The assessment of effort has been tied to Fitts’ law (MacKenzie 1992) for measurements of physical effort. However, mental effort or user-perceived effort remains unassessed.
By visualizing keystrokes, we can identify the locus of impact in any given language. In language development work it is often the case that low-usage keys in an English-QWERTY layout are replaced with “new characters” to form keyboard layouts. The consequence has been the placement of frequently used keys under weak fingers, as demonstrated by the Meꞌphaa keyboard layout below. Notice the high frequency red(dish) areas and the lower frequency blue areas. These red areas would normally be struck with the pinky fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2018-thesis-proposal/Heatmaps-of-4-keyboards/[tcf]-heatmap-with-sample-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meꞌphaa Keyboard&#34; title=&#34;Meꞌphaa Keyboard&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Figure 1: Meꞌphaa Keyboard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spanish, distributes the same amount of information across multiple fingers as shown in Figure 2 below. According to current keyboard layout theory even the Spanish keyboard is heavy on the weaker fingers of the left hand, but at least is better than the Meꞌphaa layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2018-thesis-proposal/Heatmaps-of-4-keyboards/[spa]-heatmap-with-full-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Spanish Keyboard&#34; title=&#34;Spanish Keyboard&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Figure 2: Spanish Keyboard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrasting these two languages allows us to visualize how they are different with respect to the actions of the pinky finger. It also demonstrates how the attempt to ‘conserve QWERTY’ impacts typing in minority languages. Notice how the Meꞌphaa keyboard layout replaces the Spanish〈ç〉character with a tone diacritic key. Also note that these tone diacritics are very frequent in Meꞌphaa, and create a typing imbalance. Additionally, the Meꞌphaa Saltillo〈ꞌ〉 key is also on the right side with heavy use, further contributing to the typing imbalance.
These diagrams demonstrate the part of the keyboard layout analysis that can be computed using existing GKAP methods. What linguists bring to the discussion is an awareness of linguistic components. Orthographies are not just Unicode characters, but are functional units. The encoding of a functional unit can change from orthography to orthography. This is missed by many GKAP researchers. One needs to look beyond Unicode characters and toward ratios of keystrokes to functional units.
One way that linguists look at functional units differently than “pure technologists” is in the area of tone. Snider (2014) and Hyman (2014) both argue for an analysis of tone that looks at patterns across the domain of tonal attachment (usually the word or morpheme) rather than the more structuralist and segmental view of “letter plus pitch” which is the encoding method that Unicode follows. The difference in behavior becomes clearer when we contrast reading diacritic tone marks with a language which does not use diacritical marking. Imagine the following example represents the same sentence in two different languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2018-thesis-proposal/With-and-without-tone.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tone and non-Tone marking&#34; title=&#34;Tone and non-Tone marking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tone pattern analysis (following Snider and Hyman) would suggest that we should understand the tonally marked sentence to represent the segmental and the suprasegmental tiers separately, something like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2018-thesis-proposal/High-low-pattern-over-tone-marks.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Marking representing tonal patterns or melodies&#34; title=&#34;Marking representing tonal patterns or melodies&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is observed, anecdotally, that many writers of tone languages parse the writing task into two activities, one for each tier of information. Usually the segmental tier is completed first and then the suprasegmental tier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2018-thesis-proposal/Reading-twice.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Reading twice&#34; title=&#34;Reading twice&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes the writing activity much like handwriting in the United States where we say: “don’t forget to dot your &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;s and cross your  ‘t’s. The writer first completes the segmental tier and then comes back across with a second pass and completes dots the ‘i’s and crosses the ‘t’s.
However, the nature of typing, and Unicode’s structural nature, requires typists to complete the text production task linearly by codepoint. This creates dissonance from what many language users find “natural”, requiring them to frequently alternate their attention between the two tiers, as shown by the up and down movement in the following diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2018-thesis-proposal/Up-and-down-eye-movement.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Up and down eye movement&#34; title=&#34;Up and down eye movement&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this thesis will be to develop and apply metrics to keyboard layouts so that their ease of use can be analysed and compared. Some optimised keyboards in a few sample languages will also be presented. Preliminary testing of these ideas has been done on English [eng], Spanish [spa], Me’phaa [tcf], and Chinantec [cso], as mentioned in Paterson (2014) and work done with Nigerian languages in Paterson (2015) covering Ezza [eza], Bekwarra [bkv], Cishingini [asg], Okphela [atg], and Igbo [ibo]. However, for this thesis I anticipate focusing on the three following languages: Navajo [nav], Kabiyè [kbp], and Eastern Dan [dnj], and especially the latter two, as they are related languages with very different design decisions in their orthographies, and both have very clear analysis of their tonal systems. This should allow observations about the typing process in one language to be contrasted with another related language. Further, there is a reasonable amount of text to work with in each language. Ultimately the final languages used will depend on the accessibility of corpora content in those languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thesis will add to the current GKAP discussion by proposing a theoretical framework and a two-metric algorithm that can be applied to any keyboard layout for any language using a Latin based script. The first metric will account for disruption in the phoneme (or functional unit) stream while engaged in typing, and the second will account for non-character-producing keystrokes, thus addressing the major problem areas outlined above. These metrics will then be combined with a haptic fitness score to produce a fitness score which accounts for linguistic knowledge. This thesis will contribute to the ongoing language development discussion by providing a quality assessment metric for the evaluation of a very important language-based digital product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-questions&#34;&gt;Research questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem to be addressed can be expressed informally like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have these keyboards layouts in all these languages, but they are not being used, and in general people find it easier to type in languages other than their mother tongue.  To what extent are our keyboards disruptive and thereby impeding language use in digital contexts? Can we measure the disruption?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More precisely, the following sub-questions can be addressed in the course of this investigation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What percentage of extra work is required to type minority-language texts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, the “extra work” measurement might be measured in terms of the distance traveled, the time required to travel that distance, and the number of keystrokes, as compared between a language of wider communication and a minority language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a given language, what is the added unnecessary distance when typing text?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some common traits of excessive use/difficulty in text input keyboards for minority languages, and how can those commonalities of “pain”, be generalized for designers to avoid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we account for functional units (e.g. phonemes and tones) independent from character optimization? That is, does optimizing for character input also optimize for functional unit input?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we predict that with tone languages we will exceed the Hick’s law minimum, whereas in non-tonal languages we can stay under Hick’s law?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hick’s law (Hick 1952) is a reference to how performance decreases as temporary memory functions increase, i.e., when we need to hold information in our temporary memory. This can be calculated on the basis of how many characters does one need to type in between the elements of a diacritic digraph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we measure the dissonance factor for a particular keyboard layout? That is, how much dissonance does a keyboard layout solution induce?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dissonance is the cognitively difficult, or non-prefered choices that we must make to achieve the desired results. Dissonance is increased by those things which militate  against fluidity, and includes factors such as non-correspondence between keystrokes and functional units, the elements of a digraph, and multiple keystrokes per orthographic character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-specifics&#34;&gt;Project specifics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To perform the supporting analysis I will use existing texts to form a “corpus of keystrokes” and a “corpus of functional units”. I use the corpus of texts in conjunction with the existing keyboard layout to suggest what the “keystrokes required” would have been to produce a text (assuming 100% accuracy). Given that I am working with corpora, rather than original production data, I will not have actual time-over-distance measurements. I will rather, as is the norm for working with corpora in this context, infer the time to completion for each keystroke based on previously published experiments which show the time it takes to move a finger from one key to another. Then I will look at the functional units and measure (1) how many keystrokes to functional units are required, and (2) how much dissonance is created in the process of typing.
Existing keyboard layouts for the languages of the texts in question will be analysed, and scored. Finally, improved keyboard layouts with better scores will be suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xi Bi, BA Smith, S Zhai (2012) Multilingual touchscreen keyboard design and optimization. Human–Computer Interaction 27(4), 352-382.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garrett, Jesse James (2002) The Elements of User Experience: User-Centered Design for the Web. New Riders Publishing, Thousand Oaks, CA, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hick, W. E. (1952) On the rate of gain of information. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology 4 (1): 11–26. doi:10.&lt;sup&gt;1080&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;17470215208416600&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyman, Larry M. (2014) How To Study a Tone Language, with exemplification from Oku (Grassfields Bantu, Cameroon). Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation 8.525-62.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kornai, A. (2013) Digital Language Death. PLOS ONE 8(10): e77056. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0077056&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0077056&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacKenzie, I. Scott. (1992) Fitts&amp;rsquo; law as a research and design tool in human-computer interaction. Human-Computer Interaction 7, 91-139.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paterson, Hugh J., III (2014) Keyboard layouts: Lessons from the Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec designs. In Jones, Mari C. (ed.), Endangered Languages and New Technologies, 49-66. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paterson, Hugh J., III (2015) African languages: Assessing the text input difficulty. Presentation at the 46th Annual Conference on African Linguistics, Eugene Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peng-Yeng Yin, En-Ping Su (2011) Cyber Swarm optimization for general keyboard arrangement problem., International Journal of Industrial Ergonomics 41(1), 43-52. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ergon.2010.11.007&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ergon.2010.11.007&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snider, Keith L. (2014) On Establishing Underlying Tonal Contrast. Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation 8.707-37. &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholarspace.manoa.hawaii.edu/handle/10125/24622&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://scholarspace.manoa.hawaii.edu/handle/10125/24622&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U.S. Department of Health &amp;amp; Human Services (2018) Interaction Design Basics. &lt;Accessed 2 March 2018&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usability.gov/what-and-why/interaction-design.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.usability.gov/what-and-why/interaction-design.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitsœ (2012) Dieter Rams: ten principles for good design. &lt;Accessed 27 June 2012&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vitsoe.com/en/gb/about/dieterrams/gooddesign&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.vitsoe.com/en/gb/about/dieterrams/gooddesign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U̠t-Ma&#39;in Lexicography</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-lexicography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-lexicography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project includes combining and collating several U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in databases that Becky Paterson has created over the 12 years she has worked with the U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in language community. We are also importing as many Hausa terms as possible for specific elicitation (such as regional plants and animals). The final database includes grammatical features of individual lexemes. We are including various external analyses from phonology tools. None of this data is currently public. But when it is, a link from here will be posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U̠t-Ma&#39;in oral history</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-oral-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-oral-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Becky received a grant to facilitate the collection of oral story data. The terms of the grant require her to record and archive oral histories of U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in speakers. My role in this project was to work with U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in speakers (who actually did the recordings themselves) and present these to the Becky in way that she could arrange the files for archiving. In my role I got to visit around 40 different places in 7 different dialects. All from the back of a motorbike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wasta Linux additions for the language scientist.</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-wasta-language-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-wasta-language-scientist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I should make this image the wasta logo plus all the other logos I am using.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Code Serving Endangered Languages</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2016-open-source-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2016-open-source-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citable as&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Littauer, Hugh Paterson III (2016) &lt;em&gt;Open Source Code Serving Endangered Languages&lt;/em&gt;. In: C. Soria, L. Pretorius, T. Declerck, J. Mariani, K. Scannell, Eveline Wandl-Vogt, eds., In Proceedings of LREC 2016 Collaboration and Computing for Under-Resourced Languages: Towards an Alliance for Digital Language Diversity (CCURL) Workshop. Portorož, Slovenia, 23 May, 2016. pp. 86-88.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Awesome list of Software for Endangered Languages</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2016-awesome-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2016-awesome-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Head over to Github everything is over there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linguistic Services Planning</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2015-linguistic-services-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2015-linguistic-services-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIL Communications Strategy Consulting</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-sil-ils-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-sil-ils-communications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is about creating a work environment where people are informed about the services and products that the organization is able to offer. It is about breaking down communication silos and working across corporate structures to create a unified workforce.
 I have the ongoing privilege of consulting with department heads and team leaders on interdepartmental communication and audience engagement strategies. Often this involves creative uses of technology and creating data management plans and publishing work flows. At SIL International we use &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchimp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Confluence&lt;/a&gt; to meet these communication needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIL International is over 80 years old. A majority of its staff are &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baby_boomers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Baby-boomers&lt;/a&gt;. Currently work flows, even digital ones, usually mirror processes set up in paper based work enviroments.  SIL International as an organization has organizational units of various sizes in various locations of the world. Many of these units are also distributed teams. In the broader business world the battle for effective team communications is generally characterized as a battle between &lt;em&gt;looking in the inbox&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;using the browser&lt;/em&gt; for information, collaboration, and connectivity. Tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2014/8/12/5991005/slack-is-killing-email-yes-really&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#slack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/3035927/inside-the-company-that-got-rid-of-email&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;management decisions to look for more effective team communications platforms&lt;/a&gt; have tried to push email our of use. In SIL International the very diverse nature of the workforce presents challenges to those with low-bandwidth connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use a two prong communications approach. Email and corporate blog use. For Email we use Mailchimp. For the corporate blog we use Confluence Wiki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIL International deployed Confluence company wide in 2008 as a white board for people in the organization to use within their organizational unit. By 2011 the wiki had evolved into a platform for departmental websites and had supplanted official information repositories for official documentation. This has made the platform invaluable for interdepartmental communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015 various organizational units within SIL International started to independently use Mailchimp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the highly transitional nature of SIL International staff, it is often the case that SIL staff not have the knowledge base needed to leverage the capacities of these two systems. My role is often to demonstrate features relevant to business goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have engaged with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL International Language and Culture Archive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL International Language Program Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL International Language Program Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL International External Communications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL Intellectual Property Team
&lt;!--  
Two other links are: https://www.forbes.com/sites/tykiisel/2011/11/30/ceo-bans-email/
and
https://hbr.org/2016/06/some-companies-are-banning-email-and-getting-more-done
--&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The minority language typing experience</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous work&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project follows and builds upon the project where &lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-mexico-keyboards/&#34;&gt;keyboard layouts for Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec&lt;/a&gt; were produced. This project uses data from Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec but purposely extends the scope of the analysis to include Latin and Cyrillic script languages, particularly focusing on those with diacritics which express tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to bring &amp;lsquo;natural&amp;rsquo;, intuitive, and easy to use typing experiences in the form of keyboard layout designs to minority language users. These language users often do not type in their own languages, but rather experience technology through languages other than their first language. This is in part because of the perception that their language is complex or not easy to type, which is often not an invalid observation. However, with these languages which have different and sometimes more characters than English, what does a good layout look like?
The objectives of this project are threefold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To establish a consistent method to evaluate the appropriateness of a keyboard layout for a specific language situation given a specific text sample. This needs to include &lt;code&gt;deadkeys&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; states.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This needs to account for monolingual situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This needs to account for multi-lingual situations where each language has its own keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This needs to account for multi-lingual situations where only a single keyboard is used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a best fit solution recommendation when provided the following:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A corpus of text encoded in UTF-16 or UTF-8 in any language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user selected choice between a physical keyboard layout of ANSI, ISO, or JIS
The application providing the best fit solution needs to be able to suggest a better layout, inclusive of &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; states and &lt;code&gt;deadkey&lt;/code&gt; options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess and analyze real user feedback. That is, measure the impacts of keyboards on users. Speed of typing, speed of keyboard acquisition, error rate, and results such as language choice when typing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fa fa-github fa-2x&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Project resources are split into three repos: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HughP/MLKA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MLKA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HughP/MLKA-Bash-data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MLKA-Bash-data&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HughP/MLKA-Test-Data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MLKA-Test-Data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Experience Consulting on SIL.org</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-icphs-tone-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-icphs-tone-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a poster presentation of the full published paper mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-tone-transcription/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/img/Paterson-ICPhS-2015-poster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Paterson ICPhS 2015 poster&#34; title=&#34;ICPhS Poster&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA. Poser presentation at ICPhS 2015. 18th International Conference of Phonetic Sciences. University of Glasgow: Glasgow, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though you should probably just cite the paper which is citeable as&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA.  In The Scottish Consortium for ICPhS 2015 (Ed.). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 18th International Conference of Phonetic Sciences&lt;/em&gt; Paper number 507.1-5. University of Glasgow: Glasgow, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-tone-transcription/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-tone-transcription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a poster presentation presented at the 18th International Conference of Phonetic Sciences in 2015. Links are to the poster and the 5 page paper is in the conference proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA.  In The Scottish Consortium for ICPhS 2015 (Ed.). &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 18th International Conference of Phonetic Sciences&lt;/em&gt; Paper number 507.1-5. University of Glasgow: Glasgow, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>African Languages: Assessing the text input difficulty</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-africa-assessing-the-difficulty-of-text-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-africa-assessing-the-difficulty-of-text-input/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) &lt;em&gt;African Languages: Assessing the text input difficulty&lt;/em&gt;. Paper presented at the 46th Annual Conference of African Linguistics. Held at the University of Oregon 26th-28th March 2015&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lexical dataset archiving: an assessment of practice</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-lexical-database-archiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-lexical-database-archiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) &lt;em&gt;Lexical dataset archiving: an assessment of practice&lt;/em&gt;. Poster presented at the 4th International Conference on Language Documentation and Conservation, at the Ala Moana Hotel in Honolulu, HI. February 26th – March 1st Version 1.0&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
