<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Experience | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/user-experience/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/user-experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>User Experience</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 17:00:12 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>User Experience</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/user-experience/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>XLingPaper&#39;s use of TeX technologies</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2022-xlingpapers-use-of-tex-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 17:00:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2022-xlingpapers-use-of-tex-technologies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TUG 2021 Abstracts</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2021-xlingpapers-use-of-tex-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 17:00:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2021-xlingpapers-use-of-tex-technologies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Language Archives Community Research</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2021-open-language-archives-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2021-open-language-archives-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this research project I look at the information architecture supporting the global ability to assess language resources. I look at issues such as metadata schemas, description and arrangement in archives, and the technology stack presenting OLAC. I started intently looking at OLAC resources at the end of 2020 while looking at language archives more broadly and trying to create an OLAC OAI feed. Since then I have presented at conferences and published results of my findings in several locations as my findings have bearing on the broader areas of resource stewardship and resource description.  I was invited by Steven Bird to think with him on what OLAC 2.0 might look like. That work, its results and blog posts are also linked to this &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo; page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are we upfront with the consumers of our services?</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/are-we-up-front-with-our-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 14:14:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/are-we-up-front-with-our-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are we upfront with the consumers of our services? When this comes to web data, notice how worldcat.org informs (at least in 2014) their service&amp;rsquo;s consumers. At the point of login it is simple, clear and does not use a pop-up. Such a notice allows users to make informed choices about the use of a specific service&amp;hellip; assuming they are literate in the language of the notice, understand the laws of that country, and don&amp;rsquo;t also have undue pressure to use the service anyway regardless of consqences.&lt;/p&gt;



  
  
  

&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-worldcatorg-login-notice&#34;itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/are-we-up-front-with-our-users/USA-data2_hu877bf32cbb78377c6cb9b2b226d7edb3_273346_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;worldcat.org login notice&#34;&gt;

  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/are-we-up-front-with-our-users/USA-data2_hu877bf32cbb78377c6cb9b2b226d7edb3_273346_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;Example Notice of laws governing data interactions and responsibilities.&#34; width=&#34;1349&#34; height=&#34;872&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;worldcat.org login notice
      
&lt;span class=&#34;img-attribution&#34;&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldcat.org&#34;&gt; worldcat.org&lt;span itemprop=&#34;creator&#34; itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34; itemscope&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;name&#34; content=&#34;worldcat.org&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;




  
  
  

&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-worldcatorg-login-noticecloseup&#34;itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/are-we-up-front-with-our-users/USA-Data_hu27281f63c05ac7e3c68cad3f831b2b5c_35913_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;worldcat.org login notice—closeup&#34;&gt;

  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/are-we-up-front-with-our-users/USA-Data_hu27281f63c05ac7e3c68cad3f831b2b5c_35913_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;Closeup of notice of laws governing data interactions and responsibilities.&#34; width=&#34;392&#34; height=&#34;299&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;worldcat.org login notice—closeup
      
&lt;span class=&#34;img-attribution&#34;&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldcat.org&#34;&gt; worldcat.org&lt;span itemprop=&#34;creator&#34; itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34; itemscope&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;name&#34; content=&#34;worldcat.org&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OWL and the Rice Farmer</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-owl-and-the-rice-farmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 14:14:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-owl-and-the-rice-farmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent email I was asked by a &lt;em&gt;European Linguistic Professional SIL Colleague&lt;/em&gt; about the ease of use of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.mpi.nl/tla/elan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELAN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is ELAN easy enough to use, so that an Indonesian rice farmer can use it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am offended with the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; terminology which is prevalent in SIL discourse. However, to understand this term, and its usage I think it is important to understand another term used prior to &lt;em&gt;the rice farmer&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;em&gt;The Ordinary Working Linguist&lt;/em&gt;. This older phrase has gained some traction as evidenced by its adoption in the linguistic literature&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OWL&lt;/em&gt; or &amp;lsquo;ordinary working linguist&amp;rsquo; is attributed 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icsi.berkeley.edu/icsi/blog/chuck-fillmore-dies-at-84&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;by George Lakoff&lt;/a&gt; to Charles Fillmore as a self-describing term. Though it is impossible to say if Fillmore actually coined the term. If he did, then it is an interesting frame by the discoverer of cognitive framing. I have yet to meet an &lt;em&gt;ordinary linguist&lt;/em&gt;. I have met smart linguists, extraordinary linguists, novel linguists, quirky linguists, geeky linguists, and ornery linguists — but never an &lt;em&gt;ordinary one&lt;/em&gt;. The second issue I take with this contrived frame is that it suggests that somewhere there might be a &lt;em&gt;non-working linguist&lt;/em&gt;. Now, either I have never met a lazy linguist, or I have been foiled by some collective endeavor. That is, the linguists I have met have somehow &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; decided that I am an extremely boring person — the kind to be avoided, and &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; have feigned busyness! Granted busyness is not the same as &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo;, but I have never met a linguist who is not engaged in some sort of activity which has a mistakable similitude to &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the same, the notion of &amp;ldquo;OWL&amp;rdquo; seems to be very useful to a large group of linguists. For instance, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholars.sil.org/gary_f_simons/preprint/computing_environment&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gary F. Simons suggests&lt;/a&gt; that Helen Aristar Dry proposed a book in the early 1990s with the title &lt;em&gt;Computers and the Ordinary Working Linguist.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, While David Nathan, Peter Austin, Andrew Black, Piotr Bański, Mike Cahill, Jeff Good, Steven Moran, Scott Farrar, and René van den Berg all use the term in their works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In honor of Fillmore, if we take a framing view of the phrase &amp;ldquo;ordinary working linguist&amp;rdquo; we can see that many of the authors are discussing the concept within the frame of linguistic computing — the computer tools that linguists use to do their work. However, it can be argued that there is an SIL specific shift in the framing of the phrase (usage by Cahill, Schroeder, Simons, Black, and van den Berg). Van den Berg&amp;rsquo;s use is most articulate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the typical SIL fieldworker is what has been called an ‘owl’, that is, an ‘ordinary working linguist’ who has been given enough training to enable him or her to do the job; this  is usually a minimum of  two semesters of field linguistics at graduate level. A typical SIL field worker is therefore very  much a generalist, without specialist knowledge in any branch of linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van den Berg&amp;rsquo;s usage is both confirmed and then contrasted by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20130308204655/https://www.sil.org/linguistics/people&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIL International&lt;/a&gt; on its website where it contrasts the term with &lt;em&gt;Linguistics Coordinators&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Linguistics Consultants&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;International Linguistics Advisors&lt;/em&gt;. It is clear to see that within the shared frame by SIL staff, that Linguistic Consultants are those who have more training than typical SIL field workers. For several reasons, including reduced staffing, and paradigm shifts within project management related moral ownership within the tasks of language development, SIL has moved from ex-pat driven projects to nationally staffed and ethnolinguistic community driven projects. SIL&amp;rsquo;s minimally trained &amp;ldquo;OWLs&amp;rdquo; moved up the organizational chart to become project managers/facilitators, leaving open the &amp;ldquo;bottom&amp;rdquo; of the chart, ergo the new need for &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; as a newly perceived class of computer user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the term &lt;em&gt;rice farmer&lt;/em&gt; 14 times in the internal SIL International wiki and I find &amp;ldquo;OWL&amp;rdquo; 83 times. These terms surface mostly among SIL computer app developers, but I also hear them used by SIL policy and procedures developers, SIL program planners, and SIL educators. To me this term comes off as a class distinction term (and maybe there is nothing wrong with class distinction; I mean the Jews had class distinctions at the time of Jesus, the Cretans had classes at the time of Titus, the British have it, and castes are alive and well in India, etc.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). However, as I find the term being used in SIL, a more transparent term might be &amp;lsquo;low socio-economic and low educational &lt;em&gt;capacity&lt;/em&gt; individual&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that in my work with Steve Marlett in Mexico, I worked with ethnolinguistic moronity language users who were not &amp;lsquo;low educational capacity individuals&amp;rsquo; rather they were high educational capacity individuals. When I went to Malaysia and worked with Sean Conklin, the same thing, ethnolinguistic minority language users were not low educational capacity individuals. When I went to Nigeria and worked with people like Becky Paterson and David Rowbory, the people doing language work with us were not low educational capacity individuals. In fact the Nigerian rice farmer/pastor/student/translator/cultural guide/language activist who was on our language project team can and does use ELAN after some training (and uses Facebook without training to boot — FYI: I need training on ELAN too!). So, why then do SIL staff use terms like &amp;lsquo;rice farmers&amp;rsquo; when they talk about designing software for users? Something seems to be wrong with this picture. My guess is that there is a real reason why SIL staff use the term, but it is not the reason that SIL staff attribute as the causation of the observation of &amp;ldquo;low educational capacity individuals&amp;rdquo; - as we observe dark skinned colleagues who try and use SIL software and don&amp;rsquo;t intuitively know how to use the tools. My guess is that the reason for the use of the term is because it is part of the SIL corporate ethos. SIL staff use (or at least have in the past) their educational courses at various SIL training events as filters to find the &amp;lsquo;best and brightest students&amp;rsquo; and recommend those for various field service within SIL. Then in the advanced classes SIL staff obfuscate the materials just to make them harder, to see if those same students are able to still keep up. So, as I see it, there seems to be this undefined class difference in SIL&amp;rsquo;s corporate sociology preferring those who can distill obfuscated communications under stress and dis-preferring those who cannot distill obfuscated signals under stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the following four reasons I strongly dis-prefer the terms &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;OWL&amp;rsquo; as they often appear in SIL discourse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; terminology is actually very useful for professional reasons. Software design is about communicating. It is about communicating relational concepts in a visual context. It is about connecting new analogies with salient concepts. User Interface (UI - what a software user sees and interacts with) is the gateway to User Experience (UX - the emotional, logical, task based context of activities that are attempting to be facilitated by the software designer and accomplished by the software user). Therefore what UX is really about is communicating ideas and creating positive and successful interactions. If the UI fails to create the designed UX then it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the user is a rice farmer or a Ph.D. candidate from an Australian university. The end result is that the user is frustrated and will not use the software willingly. Therefore, singling out the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; from the white guy is not really a useful construct because all users, whether black, white, tan, farmer, or stockbroker, are subject to the same constraints and frustrations of software which is not intuitively implemented. It is my experience that programmers (not just SIL programmers) usually do not intuitively know how application users think or behave. UX design is an art and a science that takes experimentation and a solid grasp of information design principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget that, at least in software design we are talking about the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; with a computer, an iPad, or an android device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We never use the American Corn Farmer, or the Norwegian Reindeer Rancher as analogies, and I am a bit tired of singling out people from tropical areas because their skin is darker, or their average height is shorter, or because they grow rice in their backyard. The focus on the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; does not help us deal with the white guy&amp;rsquo;s problem with the software and robs us of a balanced view of the real communication challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the term &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; seems to put the ethnolinguistic minority language users and nationals in a sub-standard class relative to &amp;lsquo;real linguists&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;real missionaries&amp;rsquo;. Yes, my African colleagues who do have their own farms and families, also use SIL software; I first drove a tractor at age 13 and grew up on a farm, so what is the difference? By making the &amp;lsquo;OWL&amp;rsquo; or the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; as some uninitiated or limited capacity person,  the &amp;ldquo;reason&amp;rdquo; for new design (i.e the reason that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://software.sil.org/wesay&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WeSay&lt;/a&gt; was created to work with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://software.sil.org/fieldworks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FLEx&lt;/a&gt;) doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve the fact that even for highly-educated-white-professionals FLEx is still confusing. The issue is a visual communications issue not a smarts or intelligence issue. Linguistic concepts can be communicated about beautifully and communicated simply, both in the classroom and in software. &lt;!-- also note the framing that John Hatton has taken about PhD in having training for software but nations don&#39;t in his presentation  on SayMore here: https://scholarspace.manoa.hawaii.edu/handle/10125/26153?mode=full --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this post motivates those in SIL to take a deeper look at User Experience issues in the software tools and websites we build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- also uses the term 
1. https://tel.archives-ouvertes.fr/tel-03131936/document 
2. https://doi.org/10.1515/ling-2017-0032 Reproducible research in linguistics:
A position statement on data citation and attribution in our field. 
3. https://doi.org/10.1515/lity.2002.007 Recent activity in the theory of aspect: Accomplishments, achievements, or just non-progressive state?
4. https://doi.org/10.1075/cilt.32.10lon Robert Longachre in New Directions in Linguistics and Semiotics  
5. Fellow essay: https://www.essaysinlinguistics.com/2018/09/12/fillmore/--&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bański, Piotr. 2010. Why TEI stand-off annotation doesn’t quite work: and why you might want to use it nevertheless. In Proceedings of Balisage: The Markup Conference 2010 (Balisage Series on Markup Technologies 5), n.p. Montréal, Canada: Balisage. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4242/BalisageVol5.Banski01&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4242/BalisageVol5.Banski01&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;van den Berg, René. 2013. SIL and its contribution to Oceanic linguistics. Language and Linguistics in Oceania 5. 33–74. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.izumi-syuppan.co.jp/LLO_PDF/vol_05/13Berg.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.izumi-syuppan.co.jp/LLO_PDF/vol_05/13Berg.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black, H Andrew &amp;amp; Gary F Simons. 2008. The SIL Fieldworks Language Explorer Approach to Morphological Parsing. In Nick Gaylord, Alexis Palmer &amp;amp; Elias Ponvert (eds.), Texas Linguistics Society 10: Computational Linguistics for Less-Studied Languages, 37–55. Stanford, California: CSLI Publications. &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.stanford.edu/group/cslipublications/cslipublications/TLS/TLS10-2006/TLSX-2006-toc.shtml&#34;&gt;http://web.stanford.edu/group/cslipublications/cslipublications/TLS/TLS10-2006/TLSX-2006-toc.shtml&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cahill, Mike C. 2001. Farewell from the Coordinator. Notes on Linguistics 4(4). 203–204. &lt;a href=&#34;https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED467733.pdf&#34;&gt;https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED467733.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farrar, Scott &amp;amp; Steven Moran. 2008. The e-Linguistics toolkit. In Workshop in the 4th IEEE International Conference on e-Science, Indianapolis, Indiana, 10 December 2008, n.p. IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5167/UZH-84686&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5167/UZH-84686&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good, Jeff. 2010. Valuing technology: Finding the linguist’s place in a new technological universe. In Lenore A. Grenoble &amp;amp; N. Louanna Furbee (eds.), Language Documentation: Practice and values, 111–132. Amsterdam: John Benjamins Publishing Company. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/z.158.13goo&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/z.158.13goo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan, David &amp;amp; Peter K Austin. 2004. Reconceiving metadata: language documentation through thick and thin. Language Documentation and Description 2. 179–188. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/029&#34;&gt;http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/029&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schroeder, Leila. 2008. Bantu Orthography Manual (SIL E-Books 9). Revised 2010. Dallas, Texas: SIL International. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sil.org/resources/archives/9241&#34;&gt;https://www.sil.org/resources/archives/9241&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which would be later published as: Aristar Dry, Helen &amp;amp; John Lawler (eds.). 1998. Using Computers in Linguistics: A Practical Guide. 1st edn. London: Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203059012&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203059012&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States doesn&amp;rsquo;t have classes, only more successful capitalists and less successful capitalists. — ⟨snark⟩ &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability &amp; Language Resource Stewardship</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-archive-usability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-archive-usability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this research theme, I look at avariety of usability issues from resource arrangment and description in stewardship arrangments of language resources to user interfaces to those resources. I have published several papers, given many talks and written many blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in this project the focus was more narrow and I sought to look at issues in &lt;em&gt;Language Resource Accessibility&lt;/em&gt;. My work was primarily concerned with two facets of accessibility:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;em&gt;User Experience&lt;/em&gt; related to interacting with archived content; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the aggregation of item level metadata about language resources in collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I have now expanded my resarch focus to include language resource description and arrangment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I maintain a github repo with raw data and academic outputs for earily works in project at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HughP/Lexical-Database-Archiving-Stats&#34;&gt;https://github.com/HughP/Lexical-Database-Archiving-Stats&lt;/a&gt; more recent works have their own data repositories, usually on Zenodo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
