<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digitization | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/category/digitization/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/category/digitization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Digitization</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/category/digitization/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-audio-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-audio-digitization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project involved the accession, cataloging and digitization of several collections. It also involved cataloging of multiple collections already accessioned but not yet cataloged. I was responsible for identifying and collecting metadata relevant for audio collections. I communicated with the SIL Language and Culture Archive staff when metadata schemas in place were insufficient for audio collections. I identified and recommended changes to metadata profiles used at the time by the Language and Culture Archives. I consulted industry best practices and established quality control procedures related to the digitization of cassette tapes and reel to reel tapes. I served as project manager, with a volunteer workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-photo-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-photo-digitization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I served as project manager, recruiting and supervising a volunteer workforce. Together we cataloged and scanned over 1000 photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also repatriated some photos. We took old photo albums to reunions where former SIL staff identified persons and places in the images.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-text-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-text-digitization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked with the SIL Americas Area Access Coordinator to make language materials available to translators, researchers, and language development workers. There is a wealth of information that is simply inaccessible to those who could use it. I helped in the implementation of a system to make these materials available digitally, via the internet. Access to these materials affects the mechanics of language development and translation projects throughout the Americas Area and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contributed in general to archiving processes related to text scanning, and the post processing of these scans into archival and distribution formats. I served as site manager and recruiter with a volunteer work force. I brokered accessions of older materials from their creators.
I worked with IT staff to produce an automated reporting mechanism to track team progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
-- insert photos
-- insert data progress chart --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
