<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugh Paterson III | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/author/hugh-paterson-iii/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/author/hugh-paterson-iii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hugh Paterson III</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Hugh Paterson III</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/author/hugh-paterson-iii/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Educational Resources Grant Proposal</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-grant-proposal-language-educational-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-grant-proposal-language-educational-resources/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General introduction to the Materiality of Audio objects in the study of linguistics</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-general-introduction-to-the-materiality-of-audio-related-to-linguistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-general-introduction-to-the-materiality-of-audio-related-to-linguistics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Languages &amp; Dialects: a comparison of differentiations</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-languages-and-dialects-a-comparison-of-differentiations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-languages-and-dialects-a-comparison-of-differentiations/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A schema for describing international agreements, cooperating nations and sovereign states as a sub-component in a graph database</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-sates-and-treaties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-sates-and-treaties/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asimjeeg Datooga (Southern Nilotic, Tanzania) ASR</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-richard-asr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-richard-asr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work has no written results yet. It is purely experimental at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chepang (Nepal) ASR</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-chepang-asr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-chepang-asr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work has no written results yet. It is purely experimental at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tentative: [Phonetic Description of Khroskyabs]</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-khroskyabs-phonetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-khroskyabs-phonetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an early sketch of an Yu Lha&amp;rsquo;s home variety. Our goal is to model an Illustration of the IPA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Maturity Canvas</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2019-business-maturity-canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2019-business-maturity-canvas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project was a collaboration with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/stevemoitozo2?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Steve Moitiozo&lt;/a&gt;. He generally has the conversations, and therefore provided the content fodder. I facilitated graphical design of these ideas. I provided the canvas layout and graphic design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project resulted in two tools. A canvas which helps a business &amp;ldquo;owner&amp;rdquo; or and entrepreneur discover where their business is currently and what sorts of actions they should be looking at to determine how their business fits into the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2019-business-maturity-canvas/Business-Model-Fit-canvas-v1.pdf&#34;&gt;Canvas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2019-business-maturity-canvas/Business-Model-Fit-Worksheet.pdf&#34;&gt;Worksheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tentative: [Phonetic Description of an Italian dialect]</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-italian-phonetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-italian-phonetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an early sketch of an Sara&amp;rsquo;s home variety. Our goal is to model an Illustration of the IPA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tentative: [Business Model for delivering linguistics training to Minority language speakers]</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-business-model-for-delivering-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2019-business-model-for-delivering-training/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSS, Commercial &amp; Closed source</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2018-oss-commercial-closed-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2018-oss-commercial-closed-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This draft came about because we realized that our previous 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/publication/2016-open-source-code/&#34;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; had some limitations. We want to better serve software seekers with a fuller array of actionable and useful data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about language data, licensing, and social data with respect to SIL involvement</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2017-opendata-in-sil-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2017-opendata-in-sil-contexts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIL Communication Strategy Consulting</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-sil-ils-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-sil-ils-communications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is about creating a work environment where people are informed about the services and products that the organization is able to offer. It is about breaking down communication silos and working across corporate structures to create a unified workforce.
I have the ongoing privilege of consulting with department heads and team leaders on interdepartmental communication and audience engagement strategies. Often this involves creative uses of technology and creating data management plans and publishing work flows. At SIL International we use 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchimp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Confluence&lt;/a&gt; to meet these communication needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL International is over 80 years old. A majority of its staff are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baby_boomers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Baby-boomers&lt;/a&gt;. Currently work flows, even digital ones, usually mirror processes set up in paper based work enviroments.  SIL International as an organization has organizational units of various sizes in various locations of the world. Many of these units are also distributed teams. In the broader business world the battle for effective team communications is generally characterized as a battle between &lt;em&gt;looking in the inbox&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;using the browser&lt;/em&gt; for information, collaboration, and connectivity. Tools like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2014/8/12/5991005/slack-is-killing-email-yes-really&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#slack&lt;/a&gt;, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/3035927/inside-the-company-that-got-rid-of-email&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;management decisions to look for more effective team communications platforms&lt;/a&gt; have tried to push email our of use. In SIL International the very diverse nature of the workforce presents challenges to those with low-bandwidth connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use a two prong communications approach. Email and corporate blog use. For Email we use Mailchimp. For the corporate blog we use Confluence Wiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL International deployed Confluence company wide in 2008 as a white board for people in the organization to use within their organizational unit. By 2011 the wiki had evolved into a platform for departmental websites and had supplanted official information repositories for official documentation. This has made the platform invaluable for interdepartmental communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015 various organizational units within SIL International started to independently use Mailchimp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the highly transitional nature of SIL International staff, it is often the case that SIL staff do not have the knowledge base needed to leverage the capacities of these two systems. My role is often to demonstrate features relevant to business goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have engaged with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL International Language and Culture Archive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL International Language Program Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL International Language Program Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL International External Communications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIL Intellectual Property Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--  
Two other links are: https://www.forbes.com/sites/tykiisel/2011/11/30/ceo-bans-email/
and
https://hbr.org/2016/06/some-companies-are-banning-email-and-getting-more-done
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lexical dataset archiving: an assessment of practice</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-lexical-database-archiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-lexical-database-archiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;poster-small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lexical dataset archiving: an assessment of practice&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referenceable as&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) &lt;em&gt;Lexical dataset archiving: an assessment of practice&lt;/em&gt;. Poster presented at the 4th International Conference on Language Documentation and Conservation, at the Ala Moana Hotel in Honolulu, HI. February 26th – March 1st Version 1.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bibliography-for-poster&#34;&gt;Bibliography for Poster:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bird, Steven &amp;amp; Gary F. Simons. 2003. Seven dimension of portability for language documentation and description. Language 79(3). 557–582. doi:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1353/lan.2003.0149&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1353/lan.2003.0149&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Himmelmann, Nikolaus P. 1998. Documentary and Descriptive Linguistics. Linguistics 36(1). 161–195. doi:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1515/ling.1998.36.1.161&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1515/ling.1998.36.1.161&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holton, Gary. 2012. Language archives: They’re not just for linguists any more. In Frank Seifart et al. (eds.), Potentials of Language Documentation: Methods, Analyses, and Utilization (Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation Special Publication 3), 111-7. Honolulu, Hawai&amp;rsquo;i: University of Hawai&amp;rsquo;i Press. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/4523&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/4523&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Johnson, Heidi. 2004. Language Documentation and Archiving, or How to build a better Corpus. In Peter Austin (ed.), Language Documentation and Description (2), 140-53. London, UK: SOAS. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/026&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nathan, David. 2011. Digital archiving. In Peter K. Austin &amp;amp; Julia Sallabank (eds.), The Cambridge handbook of endangered languages (Cambridge Handbooks in Language and Linguistics), 255-74. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. doi: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511975981.013&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1017/CBO9780511975981.013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woodbury, Anthony C. 2003. Defining Documentary Linguistics. In Peter K. Austin (ed.), Language Documentation and Description (1), 35-51. London: SOAS. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/006&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paterson III, Hugh &amp;amp; Jeremy Nordmoe. 2013. Challenges of implementing a tool to extract metadata from linguists: the use case of RAMP﻿. Poster presented at 3rd International Conference on Language Documentation and Conservation (ICLDC), Honolulu, Hawai&amp;rsquo;i, (2 March 2013). 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/26178&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/26178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Experience Consulting on SIL.org</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of people have lots to say about User Experience. Most of it is fancy talk for &amp;ldquo;How much can you pay me to work on your website&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. When we get beyond that level of discussion, there are some real issues and methods to building websites that people are &lt;em&gt;proud to own&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;proud to use&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s search page makes them lots of money and people use it all the time. It even won the popular search war against &lt;em&gt;Yahoo!&lt;/em&gt; Facebook has a website that millions of people use every day. At some point a well designed website stops being a website in the minds of users and becomes a place where they work, hangout, arrange meetings, etc. When users stop realizing they are on a website, that is when I feel we have moved into a place in design where we are close to perfect for that situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 2010 and 2016 I worked with a team to bring modern features via Drupal 7 to the flagship website of SIL International. But I have also worked on WordPress sites (not for SIL) since 2005. And I consulted on a variety of other SIL web projects (some of them on WordPress).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work with SIL started with a report that they were not using a &lt;code&gt;print.css&lt;/code&gt; file on the SIL Bibliography in 2006 and were wasting a lot of ink when people were printing pages. I think this was corrected by 2009. This was typical for the pace of technical innovative change. SIL is a very corporate feature focused development environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within User Experience studies, there is at least two ways to apply the term (UX): &lt;em&gt;The design of experiences that a corporation wants their customers to engage in&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;the  way that people take an object (product) and decide to use it&lt;/em&gt;. Both are important, but how a company approaches either of these facets and how they relate that approach back to their other business goals scopes the relevance of User Experience Design within the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful interactions depend on both points of view and the metrics of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL.org is an interesting use case in UX design for at least 5 reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL has several major areas of very public interactions which it engages with to various degrees in various parts of the world — but the Internet is flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocacy with public policy making bodies regarding the needs of minority language speakers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing and sales of professional resources and materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bible translation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Educational programs (both formal and workshop style) in linguistics and language development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mother tongue Multi-lingual educational programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minority language literacy (both integrated with national educational programs, and community sponsored programs, for children and adults).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NGOs and development agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative computer technology development related to non-English typesetting and computing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative creative access power solutions (like solar).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainable logistical support for difficult to access project locations (usually via air).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL has historically had a very fractured internal identity, and a very decentralized governance, which has not required a high degree of uniformity throughout the organization. Digital infrastructure projects stress these social norms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the organization web-presence has come to be regarded as the officiating act recognition of an internal group&amp;rsquo;s merit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different people within the organization have strong opinions about how the world should view the organization — which are reflected in what they think the organization should say about itself — including the interactions that the organization provides to the people who interact on its website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally, the Internet is going mobile, and SIL struggles between generating the informatic thrill need to entice donors, visual storytelling needed to facilitate product distribution and training needs of its product users, and high level information needs of politicians, and staffs of other NGOs to seed future partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantitatively, most people come to SIL.org to learn about linguistics, or the plethora of digital tools that SIL distributes via sil.org, or the vast number of resources .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
Rebranding SIL Journals

Journal of phonological description
Journal of grammatical description
Journal of descriptive and comparative dialectology
Journal of orthographic description and history
Journal of sociolinguistic description
--&gt;
&lt;!--  8 May 2013-  I sometimes wonder if Vision2025 applied to sil.org is to shut the website down and turn it off. If every language which needs a Bible Translation will have a project started by 2025. Then there really is no place left for SIL after that and why would SIL need a website then?



:: because we all believe that Bible Translation is more important than Language Development and there will be no way to share what Christ did for us in humanity after 2025 through language development.

:: because we all know that there will be no need for Bible Translation Revisions, after 2025... We got it right the first time...

:: because SIL will have spent all its time and effort preaching to partners &#34;sustainability&#34; it will have none in the end...

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives not Participating in OLAC</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2014-non-olac-language-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2014-non-olac-language-archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-of-the-paper&#34;&gt;Background of the paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OLAC is the Open Language Archive Community. This is a community of digital data collections which aggregate their holdings data to a common place so that linguists can view the data by a variety of parameters which are relevant to linguists. The two major parts of OLAC are the aggregator and  a metadata standard. The metadata standard is OAI compliant and pairs well with Dublin Core. It has been well represented in the relevant literature, including the citations listed below.
One thing we see is that very few (only two) libraries have joined in the aggregation of their holdings. Further there are very few if any archives which have been around prior to the digital age. Also absent are the any of the plethora of digital repositories which are present in a growing number of institutions around the world. The linked paper presented here is a list of archives which would benefit from advertising their collections via OLAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;olac-in-the-literature&#34;&gt;OLAC in the literature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bird, Steven &amp;amp; Gary Simons. 2001. The OLAC Metadata Set and Controlled Vocabularies. In Proceedings of ACL/EACL Workshop on Sharing Tools and Resources for Research and Education. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://arxiv.org/abs/cs/0105030&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:cs/0105030&lt;/a&gt;. (31 January, 2019).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bird, Steven, Gary F. Simons &amp;amp; Huang Chu-Ren. 2001. The Open Language Archives Community and Asian Language Resources. Proceedings of the Workshop on Language Resources in Asia, 6th Natural Language Processing Pacific Rim Symposium (NLPRS), Tokyo, November 2001.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bird, Steven, Hans Uszkoreit &amp;amp; Gary Simons. 2002. The Open Language Archives Community. Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC’02). European Language Resources Association (ELRA). &lt;a href=&#34;https://aclweb.org/anthology/papers/L/L02/L02-1017/&#34;&gt;https://aclweb.org/anthology/papers/L/L02/L02-1017/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simons, Gary F. &amp;amp; Steven Bird. 2003a. The Open Language Archives Community: An Infrastructure for Distributed Archiving of Language Resources. Literary and Linguistic Computing 18(2). 117–128. doi:10.1093/llc/18.2.117.
Simons, Gary F. &amp;amp; Steven Bird. 2003b. Building an Open Language Archives Community on the OAI foundation. Library Hi Tech 21(2). 210–218. doi:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1108/07378830310479848&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1108 /07378830310479848&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hughes, Baden. 2005. Metadata Quality Evaluation: Experience from the Open Language Archives Community. In Zhaoneng Chen, Hsinchun Chen, Qihao Miao, Yuxi Fu, Edward Fox &amp;amp; Ee-peng Lim (eds.), Digital Libraries: International Collaboration and Cross-Fertilization (Lecture Notes in Computer Science), vol. 3334, 320–329. Berlin; Heidelberg: Springer. doi: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-30544-6_34&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1007/978-3-540-30544-6_34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simons, Gary F. &amp;amp; Steven Bird. 2008. Toward a Global Infrastructure for the Sustainability of Language Resources. Proceedings of the 22nd Pacific Asia Conference on Language, Information and Computation, 20–22 November 2008, Cebu City, Philippines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hirt, Christopher, Gary Simons &amp;amp; Joan Spanne. 2009. Building a MARC-to-OLAC crosswalk: repurposing library catalog data for the language resources community. Proceedings of the 2009 joint international conference on Digital libraries - JCDL ’09, 393–394. Austin, TX, USA: ACM Press. doi:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1145/1555400.1555479&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1145 /1555400.1555479&lt;/a&gt;. (13 May, 2019).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simons, Gary F. &amp;amp; Steven Bird. 2011. OLAC: Accessing the World’s Language Resources. Presented at the Poster session on Metadata in Language Documentation and Description, Annual Meeting of the Linguistic Society of America, Pittsburgh, 6–9 January 2011. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hrelp.org/events/external/lsa2011/assets/LSA2011_BirdSimons_poster.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.hrelp.org/events/external/lsa2011/assets/LSA2011_BirdSimons_poster.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simons, Gary F. 2018. Some challenges ahead for the Open Language Archives Community. Presented at the Workshop on Data Archives and Languages of the Americas, University of Pennsylvania, LDC. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ldc.upenn.edu/sites/www.ldc.upenn.edu/files/simons.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.ldc.upenn.edu/sites/www.ldc.upenn.edu/files/simons.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (24 May, 2019).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio File Formats - A follow up to the SIL internal conversation on the Linguistics Discussion List</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2014-audio-file-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/manuscripts/2014-audio-file-formats/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
