<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text Input | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/text-input/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/text-input/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Text Input</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Text Input</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/text-input/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Death of Victor Hugos</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2019-the-death-of-victor-hugos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2019-the-death-of-victor-hugos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This version is only viewable by invite only until formally published.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>African Languages: Assessing the text input difficulty</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-africa-assessing-the-difficulty-of-text-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-africa-assessing-the-difficulty-of-text-input/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referenceable as&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) &lt;em&gt;African Languages: Assessing the text input difficulty&lt;/em&gt;. Paper presented at the 46th Annual Conference of African Linguistics. Held at the University of Oregon 26th-28th March 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bibliography-for-presentation&#34;&gt;Bibliography for Presentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bailey, Dwayne. 2007. Creating a single South African keyboard layout to promote language. Lexikos 17.1: 212-25. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ajol.info/index.php/lex/article/view/51533&#34;&gt;http://www.ajol.info/index.php/lex/article/view/51533&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bellman, Tom &amp;amp; I. Scott MacKenzie. 1998. A Probabilistic Character Layout Strategy for Mobile Text Entry. Proceedings of Graphics Interface &amp;lsquo;98, 168-76. Toronto: Canadian Information Processing Society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boerger, Brenda H. 2007. Natqgu Literacy: Capturing Three Domains for Written Language Use. Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation 1.2: 126–53.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Castellucci, Steven J. &amp;amp; I. Scott MacKenzie. 2013. Gathering Text Entry Metrics on Android Devices. Proceedings of the International Conference on Multimedia and Human-Computer Interaction - MHCI 2013, 120.1-.8. Ottawa, Canada: International ASET, Inc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooper, Gregory. 2005. Issues in the Development of a Writing System for the Kalasha Language. Ph.D dissertation, Macquarie University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Esizmetor, David Oshorenoya. 2009. What Orthography for Naijá? Paper presented at Conference on Nigerian Pidgin, University of Ibadan, Nigeria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jany, Carmen. 2010. Orthography Design for Chuxnabán Mixe. Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation 4.1: 231-53.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lewis, M. Paul &amp;amp; Gary F. Simons. 2010. Assessing endangerment: Expanding Fishman&amp;rsquo;s GIDS. Revue Roumaine de Linguistique 55.2: 103–20. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lingv.ro/RRL%202%202010%20art01Lewis.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.lingv.ro/RRL%202%202010%20art01Lewis.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacKenzie, I. Scott. 1992. Fitts&amp;rsquo; law as a research and design tool in human-computer interaction. Human-Computer Interaction 7, 91-139. doi: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327051hci0701_3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1207/s15327051hci0701_3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacKenzie, I. Scott. 2002. Introduction to this special issue on text entry for mobile computing. Human-Computer Interaction 17.2-3: 141-5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacKenzie, I. Scott. 2007. Evaluation of text entry techniques. In I. Scott MacKenzie &amp;amp; Kumiko Tanaka-Ishii (eds.), Text entry systems: Mobility, accessibility, universality, 75-101. San Francisco, CA: Morgan Kaufmann.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacKenzie, I. Scott &amp;amp; R. William Soukoreff. 2002. A Character-level Error Analysis Technique for Evaluating Text Entry Methods. A character-level error analysis technique for evaluating text entry methods. Proceedings of the Second Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction &amp;ndash; NordiCHI 2002, 241-4. New York: ACM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paterson, Hugh J., III. 2015. Assessing the difficulty of the text input task for minority languages. Paper presented at the 4th International Conference on Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation, Ala Moana Hotel in Honolulu, Hawai‘i, (February 26-March 1, 2015).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paterson, Hugh J., III. 2014. Keyboard layouts: Lessons from the Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec designs. In Mari C. Jones (ed.), Endangered Languages and New Technologies, 49-66. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soukoreff, R. William &amp;amp; I. Scott MacKenzie. 2001. Measuring errors in text entry tasks: An application of the Levenshtein string distance statistic. Extended Abstracts of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems - CHI 2001, 319-20. New York: ACM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soukoreff, R. William &amp;amp; I. Scott MacKenzie. 2003a. Metrics for text entry research: an evaluation of MSD and KSPC, and a new unified error metric. Paper presented at Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, USA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soukoreff, R. William &amp;amp; I. Scott MacKenzie. 2003b. Input-based Language Modeling in the Design of High Performance Text Input Techniques. Proceedings of Graphics Interface 2003 (CIPS, Canadian Human-Computer Communication Society), 89-96. Halifax, Nova Scotia: A K Peters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trosterud, Trond. 2012. A restricted freedom of choice: Linguistic diversity in the digital landscape. Nordlyd (Tromsø University Working Papers on Language and Linguistics) 39.2: 89-104. doi: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7557/12.2474&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.7557/12.2474&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zheltov, Pavel V. 2005. Minority languages and computerization. The situation in the Russian Federation. OGMIOS 3.3: 8-11.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the difficulty of the text input task for minority languages</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-assessing-the-difficulty-of-text-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-assessing-the-difficulty-of-text-input/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citable as:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) &lt;em&gt;Assessing the difficulty of the text input task for minority languages&lt;/em&gt;. Paper presented at the 4th International Conference on Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation, Ala Moana Hotel in Honolulu, HI. February 26th – March 1st&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard layouts: Lessons from the Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec designs</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-keyboard-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2015-keyboard-layouts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referenceable as&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugh J. Paterson III (2014) &lt;em&gt;Keyboard layouts: Lessons from the Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec designs&lt;/em&gt;. In: Endangered Languages and New Technologies edited by Mari C. Jones. pp. 49-66. Cambridge University Press. DOI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781107279063.006&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1017/CBO9781107279063.006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard layout as part of language documentation: the case of the Me&#39;phaa and Chinantec keyboards</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2012-keyboard-layout-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2012-keyboard-layout-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;watch&#34;&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Z5n77NPZC0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- This post has several items which need to be fixed. First is the link to the blog post. I think it jst needs to point to this event. Forget the blog post. another big issue is the names in the JSOn file for the language loo up. --&gt;
&lt;!-- ## Abstract

Successful writing systems today depend on electronic input methods which can be easily used for producing printed or electronic material. This paper explores keyboard design issues involved in designing two keyboards for two different established orthographies. Both orthographies are based on Latin scripts and cover a total of five minority languages in Mexico (four languages in the Meꞌphaa genus and Sochiapam Chinantec [cso] ). The design issues consider:

1. Technical differences encountered across major computer operating
systems (OS X and Windows)

2. Computer culture issues like the keyboard layout of the national language

3. Key stroke frequency of language specific segments

4. Unicode/non-Unicode issues related to character composition

Designing a Unicode keyboard for data input allowed native speakers of Meꞌphaa
to have a greater involvement in the data collected by feeding the documentation team typed data and texts in addition to providing oral data. Early adaption of digital input methods may prove to better meet the needs of both language community and researcher. By giving the language community a keyboard for their orthography the minority language speakers were given the opportunity to enter into, and use, new technological domains with their language. --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-look-a-the-types-of-orthographies-being-compared&#34;&gt;A look a the types of orthographies being compared&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-meꞌphaa-text-sample&#34;&gt;A. Meꞌphaa Text Sample&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A̱ ngui̱nꞌ, tsáanꞌ ninimba̱ꞌlaꞌ ju̱ya̱á Jesús, ga̱ju̱ma̱ꞌlaꞌ rí phú gagi juwalaꞌ ído̱ rí nanújngalaꞌ awúun mbaꞌa inii gajmá. Numuu ndu̱ya̱á málaꞌ rí ído̱ rí na̱ꞌnga̱ꞌlaꞌ inuu gajmá, nasngájma ne̱ rí gakon rí jañii a̱kia̱nꞌlaꞌ ju̱ya̱á Ana̱ꞌlóꞌ, jamí naꞌne ne̱ rí ma̱wajún gúkuálaꞌ. I̱ndo̱ó máꞌ gíꞌmaa rí ma̱wajún gúkuálaꞌ xúgíí mbiꞌi, kajngó ma̱jráanꞌlaꞌ jamí ma̱ꞌne rí jañii a̱kia̱nꞌlaꞌ, asndo rí náxáꞌyóo nitháan rí jaꞌyoo ma̱nindxa̱ꞌlaꞌ. [I̱yi̱i̱ꞌ rí niꞌtháán Santiágo̱ 1:2-4]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b-sochiapam-chinantec-text-sample&#34;&gt;B. Sochiapam Chinantec Text Sample&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hnoh² reh², ma³hiún¹³ hnoh² honh² lɨ³ua³ cáun² hi³ quiunh³² náh², quí¹ la³ cun³ hi³ má²ca³lɨ³ ñíh¹ hnoh² jáun² hi³ tɨ³ jlánh¹ bíh¹ re² lı̵́²tɨn² tsú² hi³ jmu³ juenh² tsı̵́³, nı̵́¹juáh³ zia³² hi³ cá² lau²³ ca³tɨ²¹ hi³ taunh³² tsú² jáun² ta²¹. Hi³ jáun² né³, chá¹ hnoh² cáun² honh², hi³ jáun² lı̵́¹³ lɨ³tɨn² hnoh² re² hi³ jmúh¹³ náh² juenh² honh², hi³ jáun² hnoh² lı̵́¹³ lı̵́n³ náh² tsá² má²hún¹ tsı̵́³, tsá² má²ca³hiá² ca³táunh³ ca³la³ tán¹ hián² cu³tí³, la³ cun³ tsá² tiá² hi³ lɨ³hniauh²³ hí¹ cáun² ñí¹con² yáh³. [Jacobo Jmu² Cáun² Sí² Hi³ Ca³tɨn¹ Tsá² *Judíos, Tsá² Má²tiáunh¹ Ñí¹ Hliáun³ 1:2-4]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c-spanish-text-sample&#34;&gt;C. Spanish Text Sample&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hermanos míos, gozaos profundamente cuando os halléis en diversas pruebas, sabiendo que la prueba de vuestra fe produce paciencia. Pero tenga la paciencia su obra completa, para que seáis perfectos y cabales, sin que os falte cosa alguna. [Santiago 1:2-4 Reina-Valera 1995 (RVR1995)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d-english-text-sample&#34;&gt;D. English Text Sample&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear brothers and sisters, when troubles come your way, consider it an opportunity for great joy. For you know that when your faith is tested, your endurance has a chance to grow. So let it grow, for when your endurance is fully developed, you will be perfect and complete, needing nothing. [James 1:2-4 New Living Translation (NLT 2007)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
