<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Language Documentation | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/language-documentation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/language-documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Language Documentation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 14:35:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/language-documentation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microphone Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/microphone-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 14:35:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/microphone-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time I get asked what set up I recommend for linguists&amp;rsquo; to use when they are making field recordings. The requests often go like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings, I&amp;rsquo;m writing because I am just about to head out to do field work for my degree and I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if you have any advice on the latest audio recorders for linguistic fieldwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My response is invariably to pivot and respond to the question by asking what sort of products they would like to make. That is, linguists need to think about what can be done with the recordings, and how they need to influence the audio product&amp;rsquo;s creation and future use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making good audio recordings is about making recordings someone will want to listen to again, and again, and again. Invariably researchers (linguists) will listen to their recordings over and over again as they transcribe them. However their recordings gain value when others also want to listen to them. I recently was listening to a presentation where the presenter from Brazil, demonstrated some audio recordings from his field work. He showed a picture of the recording set up. In the picture it showed that he was using a Zoom H4n. In the recordings it was evident that the gain on the mics was pumped really high. The picture showed that he was using the built in mics. In the recording, the background noise was really full front while the speaker was perceptually distant — the chicken and the noise floor (the sound of &amp;ldquo;air&amp;rdquo; in the recording) were louder than the language speaker. Controlling for these factors are fundamental issues in basic crafting of audio recordings. Craftsmen (and women) who appreciate their art will get the tools they need to make their art (and artifacts) usable and enjoyable. This presenter from Brazil, played a recording from a language in which there are only about 8 speakers left&amp;hellip; linguistically the language is already like a classic car with low mileage—RARE. However, a good recording of a rare language is like a classic car dipped in gold. Microphone choice and placement allows the audio craftsman to tune down the gain, get closer to the subject and thereby record at levels where the signal to noise ratio (the sound of &amp;ldquo;air&amp;rdquo;) and the chickens are not heard in the recording or are perceptively in the far background rather than in the foreground&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The ability to attenuate a listener to specific parts of the audio stream is where the artistry and the skill comes into full view. It is this applied artistry that makes audio recordings valued and worth listing to over and over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to audio craftsmen, linguists are generally not interested in good sounding audio, they are only interested in completing their dissertation or the next published article which proves their theoretical hypothesis or generates points with their tenure and promotion board. Audio artifacts (recordings) are not primary products of interest to a linguist, rather it is what is done with them that is of their concern. This whole approach to language recording militants against good audio recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One linguist with whom I collaborated, when asked how they wanted to manage the recordings (both the technical aspect of production, and the file system organization of the recordings) was not concerned with either. That person was (at the time) ambivalent because their advisor was advising the PhD dissertation not some fieldwork project. That linguist&amp;rsquo;s goal wasn&amp;rsquo;t to produce a body of work (recordings) which could be used beyond the dissertation, the goal was to do enough fieldwork to complete the dissertation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the advisor&amp;rsquo;s perspective, as long as the fieldwork produced some written data to present in the dissertation the core requirements were satisfied. I followed the career of that linguist and now they are in a post-doc at a reputable organization. The post-doc was advertised pre-COVID and included funding for fieldwork. However, due to COVID this linguist has relied on their prior field recordings in (presumably) unexpected ways. The organization and quality of the recordings impacts their productivity as they now need to reference those recordings. Within the context of the current post-doc and the global climate, job performance productivity is not evaluated as being above average or below average. However, the career building blocks for the next post-doc or position is impacted, by how the fieldwork situation and production process was managed, and the quality of the product produced. I notice that career scholars produce about four publications a year in addition to the grants that they write and win. This is a very different interactive context than negotiating interpersonal relationships on a funded project (in a lab or in a village).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a audio craftsman, I use an an 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microphonemadness.com/products/mmdpsm.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MMaudio DPSM-SIL mic&lt;/a&gt; or one of two 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rode.com/microphones/m3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Røde M3 mics&lt;/a&gt; with a Zoom H4n digital audio recorder.  The MMaudio mic is a special set up of the mmdpsm mic with longer cords (7 feet). To order it one must call the company because they don&amp;rsquo;t put the part on-line. I think there are a few other tweaks with the DPSM-SIL and the regularly advertised DPSM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not use Phantom power with the DPSM-SIL there is a setting through the menu of the Zoom H4n that says &amp;ldquo;plug-in power&amp;rdquo;. Turn this on.  Also be careful of plugging in the mic into things like computers. I do not know what specific computer&amp;rsquo;s mic jack setting are but they might over power the mic and damage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are technical reasons related to mic sensitivity and faithfulness to the input which lead me to choose these two mics in 2008. However, for me the ability to plan how audio should sound and the ability to create &amp;ldquo;three dimensional texture&amp;rdquo; within the audio recording is more important than a specific microphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a craftsman I also suggest the use of headphones because live recordings need active monitoring. Hearing the recording is import to the production production process — what is on the recording is not what is heard in the recording environment. See my write up on headphones I have used here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hugh.thejourneyler.org/2011/headphones-for-language-documentation&#34;&gt;https://hugh.thejourneyler.org/2011/headphones-for-language-documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a different audio recording in a language archive which demonstrates the &amp;ldquo;air&amp;rdquo; and high-pitch noise induced into the recording. Presumably the high frequency pitch comes from the computer fan which is running nearby while recording. However, given the date of recording it might be the noise of the tape deck. The archive record does not make clear the original medium of recordings. From a sound engineer&amp;rsquo;s point of view, this is not great recording because the noise to signal ratio is really out of proportion. The recording is by Laurent Fontaine. Created in 2005. Titled: Histoire de Kanumá. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.24397/pangloss-0000495&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.24397/pangloss-0000495&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>u̱t‑Maꞌin oral histories and narratives</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-oral-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 09:30:22 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-oral-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Becky received a grant to facilitate the collection of oral story data. The terms of the grant require her to record and archive oral histories of U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in speakers. My role in this project was to work with U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in speakers (who actually did the recordings themselves) and present these to the Becky in way that she could arrange the files for archiving. In my role I got to visit around 40 different places in 7 different dialects. All from the back of a motorbike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chepang annotated bibliography</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2020-chepang-bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2020-chepang-bibliography/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U̠t-Ma&#39;in Lexicography</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-lexicography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-lexicography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project includes combining and collating several U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in databases that Becky Paterson has created over the 12 years she has worked with the U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in language community. We are also importing as many Hausa terms as possible for specific elicitation (such as regional plants and animals). The final database includes grammatical features of individual lexemes. We are including various external analyses from phonology tools. None of this data is currently public. But when it is, a link from here will be posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic resources for Ethno-arts in Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/ethnoarts-research-in-nigeria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 01:41:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/ethnoarts-research-in-nigeria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a quick review of the literature before a general language documentation project in Northern Nigeria. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable-authors&#34;&gt;Notable Authors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/music/contactsandpeople/profiles/villepastour.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Amanda Villepastour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vicki Brennan
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2013. &amp;ldquo;Up Above the River Jordan&amp;rdquo;: Hymns and Historical Consciousness in the Cherubim and Seraphim Churches of Nigeria. Studies in World Christianity 19 (1): 31-49&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2012. Take Control: The Labor of Immediacy in Yoruba Christian Music. Journal of Popular Music Studies 24 (4): 411-429.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2012. “Truly we have a good heritage”: Musical Mediations in a Yoruba Christian Diaspora. Journal of Religion in Africa 42 (1): 3-25.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2010. Mediating “The Voice of the Spirit”: Musical and Religious Transformations in Nigeria’s Oil Boom. American Ethnologist 37 (2): 354-370.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;database-indexes&#34;&gt;Database indexes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;africana-periodical-literature-bibliographic-database&#34;&gt;Africana Periodical Literature bibliographic database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within that database I found the following article which is relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omibiyi-Obidike, Mosunmola. 1982. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.africabib.org/rec.php?RID=186503776&amp;amp;DB=p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ethnomusicology in Nigeria&lt;/a&gt;.Bulletin of the International Committee on Urgent Anthropological and Ethnological Research. 	24. 105-112.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article reviews the current state of etbno-musicological research in Nigeria. The emergence of ethnomusicology in Nigeria is traced; assessed is what has been done so far. Examples of available materials are given and suggestions offered for future development. Approached from a historical viewpoint, the topic is discussed under the headings: the colonial, pre-independence and post-independence periods. Ref.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;archives&#34;&gt;Archives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Washington: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://music.washington.edu/ethnomusicology-visiting-artists-archive&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Visiting scholars archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Indiana: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiana.edu/~libarchm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Archives of Traditional Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dissertations&#34;&gt;Dissertations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-development-of-a-sociocultural-curriculum-in-nigerian-studies--an-integration-of-ethnomusicology-and-social-studies&#34;&gt;The development of a sociocultural curriculum in Nigerian studies : an integration of ethnomusicology and social studies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/2429/23048&#34;&gt;http://hdl.handle.net/2429/23048&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study was to develop a curriculum for ethnomusicological education in Nigerian elementary schools based on the integration of ethnomusicology and social studies. The aims of the curriculum were identified so as to be consistent with the aims of the Nigerian education system and in particular with the recently expressed aims of the Nigerian social studies curriculum which is intended to foster inter- and cross-ethnic communication and understanding and national identity in a country which contains more than 250 ethnic groups. A consideration of appropriate curriculum content led to the identification of five basic concepts in ethnomusicology and five concepts basic to social studies. The integration of these concepts into a unified curriculum was made through an Identity Approach which permitted the identification of relevant cognitive, affective and skill objectives and indicated appropriate learning processes. Three curriculum units were developed in detail and field tested in upper elementary classes in two elementary schools in southeastern Nigeria. This field testing—the classroom phase of the curriculum development— involved 120 students, ten teachers and the administrators of the schools. The staff were given instruction in the curriculum materials and the Identity Approach following which the students were engaged in twenty-four sessions and covered the three units which had been developed. The results of the classroom phase were studied from students&amp;rsquo;, teachers&amp;rsquo; and administrators&amp;rsquo; opinions and recommendations and their responses to four opinionaires. All responses indicated a high degree of student interest in the project and evidence of an increase in inter-and cross-ethnic understanding and respect. Teachers found the project to have contributed to their professional development and both teachers and administrators reported community interest and involvement. Problems identified by the staff and administrators related to inadequate funds and provision of materials or equipment. Administrators also noted the need for involvement by the Ministry of Education if widespread implementation were to be contemplated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;journals&#34;&gt;Journals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some journals which have or have have had relevant Ethnomusicology discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jmaa.uct.ac.za/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of the Musical Arts in Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journal of Popular Music Studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brill.com/view/journals/jra/jra-overview.xml?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Religion in Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;American Ethnologist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.euppublishing.com/loi/swc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Studies in World Christianity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Musicology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mission Frontiers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Journal of Pan African Studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethnomusicology Review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ethnomusicology.org/?Pub_JournalJSTOR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ethnomusicology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pacific Review of Ethnomusicology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aawmjournal.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Analytical Approaches to World Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waterman, Christopher Alan. 1990. Jùjú : a social history and ethnography of an African popular music (Chicago studies in ethnomusicology). Chicago: University of Chicago Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Myers, Helen. 1992. Ethnomusicology: Historical and Regional Studies. New York: W.W. Norton.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post, Jennifer C. 2011. Ethnomusicology: a research and information guide, 2nd edn. New York: Routledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SIL archive and its two sided markets</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-sil-archive-and-its-two-sided-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 01:41:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-sil-archive-and-its-two-sided-markets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about the language data marketplace (exchange if one prefers), and the role of archives in a world where minority language speakers are also internet users and digital file consumers. In particular I have been thinking about 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sil.org/resources/language-culture-archives&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIL’s Language and Culture Archive&lt;/a&gt; and the economic model called a 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Two-sided_market&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;two sided market&lt;/a&gt;. So, SIL as “Partners in Language Development” seems to be well situated for analysis using the two sided market analysis (matching linguist and professionals with language development skills, and persons with language development skills with interested parties in developing their language). On the surface, it seems that the SIL archive would also benefit from being the center of exchange between these same two groups. This is the subject of one of my slides for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2013-challenges-ramp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;an upcoming presentation&lt;/a&gt;, therefore I sketched out the interactions various SIL staff might have with the archive to see if I could diagram the social interactions around language data in SIL’s two sided market. To my surprise, the two sided nature of access to data in the archive is not supported, thereby blocking a data-centric archiving service. It makes me wonder what the perceived value of the archive really is, and if the perceived value is low, then why bother? What is the return on investment (ROI) for users on either side of the market?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to summarize the relationships between the various clients of the archive in the following image.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-sil-archive-and-its-two-sided-markets/SIL-Archive-and-its-two-sided-markets.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SIL Archive and its two multi-sided market representation&#34; title=&#34;SIL Archive and its two multi-sided market representation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec Keyboards</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project formalized my interest in the text input problem. While doing text input for the Meꞌphaa language documentation project it was imperative to get Unicode encoded texts. I worked with Kevin Cline to create OS X and native Windows OS keyboards for Meꞌphaa writers.  We used 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://scripts.sil.org/ukelele&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ukelele&lt;/a&gt; to create the OS X keyboards and  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170202084913/https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/globalization/keyboardlayouts.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microsoft Keyboard Layout Creator (MSKLC)&lt;/a&gt; to create the Windows keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon hearing of my new found skills, language users from the Sochiapam Chinantec community asked me to make an OS X keyboard for their language. In both cases existing keyboard layouts were matched to synchronize the user experience across the OSes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the design choices in the original layouts did not make sense to me. Hence the birth of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-expereince/&#34;&gt;The minority language typing experience&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geo-Linguistics</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-geo-linguistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-geo-linguistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are seven major sub-areas of this project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explaining cartographic concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explaining and reviewing tools for generating and processing the necessay data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating population density visualizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collecting place names and generating a map in Nigeria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a map of the language documentation files in the Meꞌphaa language documentation project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a map of the language documentation files in the U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in language documentation project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating several maps for Dan related to my M.A. thesis work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;!-- Map making tools

Import geo-names into QGIS: http://forum.geonames.org/gforum/posts/list/67.page
QGIS to illustrator: https://vimeo.com/124793295
Georeferencing Topo Sheets and Scanned Maps: http://www.qgistutorials.com/en/docs/georeferencing_basics.html

https://mygeodata.cloud/converter/svg-to-kml
https://bitbucket.org/tbrugz/kmlutils/wiki/HOWTO.en
https://freegeographytools.com/2009/convertreproject-shapefiles-and-kml-files-to-svg-format-with-indiemapper

https://bitbucket.org/voron-raven/maps

Filter country shapes: https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Osmfilter --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;File-man.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hugh in recording&#34;&gt;
Grammarian of digital file names is the loneliest job of them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mexico.sil.org/publications/i-wpindex/work_papers_-_mephaa_grammar_files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Corpus of descriptive work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdental approximant</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-interdental-approximant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 08:18:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-interdental-approximant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research project was spearheaded by Ken Olson. As a collaborator with him I focused on the historical linguistics status of the interdental approximant in Philippine languages. I also did a lot of library resources discovery and acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project description I have listed more than my contribution because I am not sure there is anywhere else that has pulled together the combined research on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results &amp;amp; Significance&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultrasound Study on the articulation of the interdental approximant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published phonetic descriptions of the interdental approximant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic Output&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publications&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mielke, Jeff, Kenneth S. Olson, Adam Baker &amp;amp; Diana Archangeli. 2011. Articulation of the Kagayanen interdental approximant: An ultrasound study. Journal of Phonetics 39(3). 403–412. DOI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.wocn.2011.02.008&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1016/j.wocn.2011.02.008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olson, Kenneth S., Emy T. Ballenas &amp;amp; Nilo M. Borromeo. 2009. Buhi’non (Bikol) digital wordlist: Presentation form. Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation 3(2). 213–225. URI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/4440&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/4440&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olson, Kenneth S., Glenn Machlan &amp;amp; Nelson Amangao. 2008. Minangali (Kalinga) digital wordlist: Presentation form. Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation 2(1). 141–156. URI 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/1772&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/1772&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olson, Kenneth S. &amp;amp; Jeff Mielke. 2008. Acoustic properties of the interdental approximant in Kagayanen. Journal of the Acoustical Society of America 123(5). 3460. DOI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2934307&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1121/1.2934307&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Academic Work&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew Harley (2012) Unusual sounds in Nigerian languages. In Advances in Minority Language Research in Nigeria Part I (eds.) Roger M. Blench and Stuart McGill. Kay Williamson Educational Foundation African languages Monographs No. 5. pages: 38-65. Rüdiger Köppe Verlag: Köln&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow-up work&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that the interdental approximant [ð̞] in Austronesian languages should challenge linguists in three important areas and thus deserves more thought and perhaps application in our theories. These categories are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The phonological status and interactions that happen with the segment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The phonetic contrast of the segment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Historical status of the segment and the impact of its recognition in the Austronesian historical linguistic narrative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications to date have focused on two relevant aspects of the interdental approximant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ð̞ is important in descriptive linguistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ð̞ is different phonetically from other described segments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following remain to be shown clearly in appropriate publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phonetic contrast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the duration of the sound and what are the boarders?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure the stable section?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where does it stop and where does it begin?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the acoustical (in terms of both production and perception) difference between /l/ and /ð̞ /?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ulturasound study does provide a good starting point to answer these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ it has a unique spectrograph when compared with other liquids, vowels, and interdentals - especially within the same language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is different from the native sounds of { l, a, ɐ, n, ʔ, d, g, r, s, h, x} which occur in Philippine languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This has been done in small phonology descriptions but not full scale acoustically reference-able phonetic descriptions across the entire set of languages discussed in the &lt;em&gt;JIPA&lt;/em&gt; article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is different from the borrowed sounds of { l, a, ɐ, n, ʔ, d, g, θ, ð, r, s, h, x, ɣ}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of psycholinguistics the question remains,: &lt;em&gt;What are the unique properties of this sound as they are culturally defined?&lt;/em&gt; or to put this another way: &lt;em&gt;What are the acustic cues, what are the visual cues, and what are the cultural constraints that those cues may violate?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research position suggests that there has been change. Change involves a variety of cognitive processes. Re-analysis is one such process. If I hypothesize that re-analysis has occurred, then what is the Cognitive load of this segment? How has that load shifted or why can it shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the unique properties that users attribute to this segment as cross-linguistically defined (but keeping within Austronesian or the Austro-Tai hypotheses).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are those unique properties as Universally or empirically defined?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Historical Narrative&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an open question with relationship to historical Austronesian as to what the metrical structure of the language was. If we posit some change in the metical structrue what relevance does that have on the interdental approximant? Does the concept of Phonetic Gemination apply?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some theories of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austro-Tai_languages&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Austro-Tai&lt;/a&gt; there is some relevance to constructing suprasegmental features and genisis or de-genesis processes for these features. In that contexts: &lt;em&gt;Is it possible that ð̞ is a tone bearing unit? (TBU)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interdental is contrastive with dental in Place in the IPA Chart
ð̞ is important to PAn Historical Phonology Theory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is related to several mergers and splits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is PAn *R&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ Shows that [+Nasal], historically, is, or is/and a super-segmental feature in Austronesian languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ shows that there are fewer proto-phonemes than necessary in current models
of PAn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ helps us to understand the PAn foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ was represented in the baybin original orthography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is relevant enough to be represented consistently in orthographies in the
languages it occurs in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phonology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several open phonological questions. Some of these have answers in the cited materials, but the data is not always clear for all languages which also have interdental approximants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the claimed Phonemes of kangayen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be all the more the claim that ð̞ is phonemic not due to a split. If it is a retention then this perspective has more weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the ð̞ pattern concerning natural classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a feature geometry perspective, what features does ð̞ have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Austornesian language have Metathesis. Is this metathesis process triggered in any way by the ð̞?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ has moraic value - what is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the affect of ð̞ on vowel quality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways can we measure the impact that ð̞ has on cognitive load?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the ð̞ occur in multiple areas of the lexicon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this a survey of the texts should be used to evaluated the
location of ð̞ in the lexicon. One resource for texts could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grayden, Bruce. 1978. &amp;ldquo;Southern Kalinga [language text].&amp;rdquo; In Evan L. Antworth (ed.),
Folktale texts, 13-23. Studies in Philippine Linguistics, 2(2). Manila: Linguistic Society of the Philippines and Summer Institute of Linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I want to research?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I want to research it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the Problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the Solution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I want to Say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the continued importance of a feature analysis to the field of descriptive linguistics and to the field of historical linguistics and to the field of Phonology?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
