<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UX | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/ux/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/ux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>UX</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>UX</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/ux/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wasta Linux additions for the language scientist.</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-wasta-language-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-wasta-language-scientist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#I should make this image the wasta logo plus all the other logos I am using.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The minority language typing experience</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous work&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project follows and builds upon the project where 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/project/2012-mexico-keyboards/&#34;&gt;keyboard layouts for Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec&lt;/a&gt; were produced. This project uses data from Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec but purposely extends the scope of the analysis to include Latin and Cyrillic script languages, particularly focusing on those with diacritics which express tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to bring &amp;lsquo;natural&amp;rsquo;, intuitive, and easy to use typing experiences in the form of keyboard layout designs to minority language users. These language users often do not type in their own languages, but rather experience technology through languages other than their first language. This is in part because of the perception that their language is complex or not easy to type, which is often not an invalid observation. However, with these languages which have different and sometimes more characters than English, what does a good layout look like?
The objectives of this project are threefold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To establish a consistent method to evaluate the appropriateness of a keyboard layout for a specific language situation given a specific text sample. This needs to include &lt;code&gt;deadkeys&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This needs to account for monolingual situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This needs to account for multi-lingual situations where each language has its own keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This needs to account for multi-lingual situations where only a single keyboard is used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a best fit solution recommendation when provided the following:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A corpus of text encoded in UTF-16 or UTF-8 in any language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user selected choice between a physical keyboard layout of ANSI, ISO, or JIS
The application providing the best fit solution needs to be able to suggest a better layout, inclusive of &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; states and &lt;code&gt;deadkey&lt;/code&gt; options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess and analyze real user feedback. That is, measure the impacts of keyboards on users. Speed of typing, speed of keyboard acquisition, error rate, and results such as language choice when typing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fa fa-github fa-2x&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Project resources are split into three repos: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HughP/MLKA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MLKA&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HughP/MLKA-Bash-data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MLKA-Bash-data&lt;/a&gt;, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HughP/MLKA-Test-Data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MLKA-Test-Data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Experience Consulting on SIL.org</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of people have lots to say about User Experience. Most of it is fancy talk for &amp;ldquo;How much can you pay me to work on your website&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. When we get beyond that level of discussion, there are some real issues and methods to building websites that people are &lt;em&gt;proud to own&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;proud to use&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s search page makes them lots of money and people use it all the time. It even won the popular search war against &lt;em&gt;Yahoo!&lt;/em&gt; Facebook has a website that millions of people use every day. At some point a well designed website stops being a website in the minds of users and becomes a place where they work, hangout, arrange meetings, etc. When users stop realizing they are on a website, that is when I feel we have moved into a place in design where we are close to perfect for that situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 2010 and 2016 I worked with a team to bring modern features via Drupal 7 to the flagship website of SIL International. But I have also worked on WordPress sites (not for SIL) since 2005. And I consulted on a variety of other SIL web projects (some of them on WordPress).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work with SIL started with a report that they were not using a &lt;code&gt;print.css&lt;/code&gt; file on the SIL Bibliography in 2006 and were wasting a lot of ink when people were printing pages. I think this was corrected by 2009. This was typical for the pace of technical innovative change. SIL is a very corporate feature focused development environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within User Experience studies, there is at least two ways to apply the term (UX): &lt;em&gt;The design of experiences that a corporation wants their customers to engage in&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;the  way that people take an object (product) and decide to use it&lt;/em&gt;. Both are important, but how a company approaches either of these facets and how they relate that approach back to their other business goals scopes the relevance of User Experience Design within the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful interactions depend on both points of view and the metrics of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL.org is an interesting use case in UX design for at least 5 reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL has several major areas of very public interactions which it engages with to various degrees in various parts of the world — but the Internet is flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocacy with public policy making bodies regarding the needs of minority language speakers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing and sales of professional resources and materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bible translation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Educational programs (both formal and workshop style) in linguistics and language development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mother tongue Multi-lingual educational programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minority language literacy (both integrated with national educational programs, and community sponsored programs, for children and adults).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NGOs and development agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative computer technology development related to non-English typesetting and computing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative creative access power solutions (like solar).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainable logistical support for difficult to access project locations (usually via air).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIL has historically had a very fractured internal identity, and a very decentralized governance, which has not required a high degree of uniformity throughout the organization. Digital infrastructure projects stress these social norms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the organization web-presence has come to be regarded as the officiating act recognition of an internal group&amp;rsquo;s merit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different people within the organization have strong opinions about how the world should view the organization — which are reflected in what they think the organization should say about itself — including the interactions that the organization provides to the people who interact on its website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally, the Internet is going mobile, and SIL struggles between generating the informatic thrill need to entice donors, visual storytelling needed to facilitate product distribution and training needs of its product users, and high level information needs of politicians, and staffs of other NGOs to seed future partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantitatively, most people come to SIL.org to learn about linguistics, or the plethora of digital tools that SIL distributes via sil.org, or the vast number of resources .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
Rebranding SIL Journals

Journal of phonological description
Journal of grammatical description
Journal of descriptive and comparative dialectology
Journal of orthographic description and history
Journal of sociolinguistic description
--&gt;
&lt;!--  8 May 2013-  I sometimes wonder if Vision2025 applied to sil.org is to shut the website down and turn it off. If every language which needs a Bible Translation will have a project started by 2025. Then there really is no place left for SIL after that and why would SIL need a website then?



:: because we all believe that Bible Translation is more important than Language Development and there will be no way to share what Christ did for us in humanity after 2025 through language development.

:: because we all know that there will be no need for Bible Translation Revisions, after 2025... We got it right the first time...

:: because SIL will have spent all its time and effort preaching to partners &#34;sustainability&#34; it will have none in the end...

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec Keyboards</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project formalized my interest in the text input problem. While doing text input for the Meꞌphaa language documentation project it was imperative to get Unicode encoded texts. I worked with Kevin Cline to create OS X and native Windows OS keyboards for Meꞌphaa writers.  We used 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://scripts.sil.org/ukelele&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ukelele&lt;/a&gt; to create the OS X keyboards and  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170202084913/https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/globalization/keyboardlayouts.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microsoft Keyboard Layout Creator (MSKLC)&lt;/a&gt; to create the Windows keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon hearing of my new found skills, language users from the Sochiapam Chinantec community asked me to make an OS X keyboard for their language. In both cases existing keyboard layouts were matched to synchronize the user experience across the OSes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the design choices in the original layouts did not make sense to me. Hence the birth of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-expereince/&#34;&gt;The minority language typing experience&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Archive Usability</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-archive-usability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-archive-usability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project seeks to make known issues in &lt;em&gt;Language Resource Accessibility&lt;/em&gt;. It is primarily concerned with two facets of accessibility:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;em&gt;User Experience&lt;/em&gt; related to interacting with archived content; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the aggregation of item level metadata about language resources in collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
