<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Becky&#39;s Curriculum Vitae on Becky&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Becky&#39;s Curriculum Vitae on Becky&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rebecca Paterson &amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:09:24 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/Becky-CV/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On the development of two progressive constructions in U̱t-Ma&#39;in</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2019-on-the-development-of-two-progressives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:09:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2019-on-the-development-of-two-progressives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;: Paterson, Rebecca Dow. 2019. On the development of two progressive constructions in U̠t-Ma’in. Folia Linguistica Historica 40 (2): 509-554. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/flih-2019-0020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10.1515/flih-2019-0020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>u̱t-Ma&#39;in reported speech</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/reported-speech-in-utmatin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:30:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/reported-speech-in-utmatin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/speechreporting/home?authuser=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Discourse reporting in African storytelling&lt;/a&gt; is a collaborative project hosted at CNRS-LLACAN, Villejuif, France. With 20+ project team members and collaborators, we are interested in traditional oral storytelling practices across West Africa. Specifically, we are investigating the relationship between specific discourse patterns and the linguistic strategies they rely on in quoted speech  and other reported speech environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nominalization and predication in U̱t-Ma&#39;in</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2019-dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:09:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2019-dissertation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;: Paterson, Rebecca Dow Smith.  2019. &lt;em&gt;Nominalization and predication in U̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in&lt;/em&gt;. Ph. D Dissertation, University of Oregon. Eugene, Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrative uses of the u̱t-Ma&#39;in (Kainji) Bare Verb form</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2015-narrative-uses-of-utmatin-bare-verb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 09:23:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2015-narrative-uses-of-utmatin-bare-verb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;: Paterson, Rebecca D. 2015. &lt;em&gt;Narrative uses of the u̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in (Kainji) Bare Verb form&lt;/em&gt;. In Doris L. Payne and Shahar Shirtz (eds.), Beyond aspect: the expression of discourse functions in African languages (Typological Studies in Language 109), 219–248. Amsterdam: John Benjamins Publishing Company. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/tsl.109.08pat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10.1075/tsl.109.08pat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;: The content of this publication was &lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/Becky-CV/talk/2013-discourse-fucntion-of-marked-and-un-marked-verbs-in-utmain/&#34;&gt;first presented&lt;/a&gt; at SLE 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discourse function of marked and unmarked verbs in u̱t-Ma&#39;in narrative</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/talk/2013-discourse-fucntion-of-marked-and-un-marked-verbs-in-utmain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/talk/2013-discourse-fucntion-of-marked-and-un-marked-verbs-in-utmain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paterson, Rebecca Dow Smith. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Discourse function of marked and unmarked verbs in u̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in narrative&lt;/em&gt;. Presentation at the workshop on &amp;ldquo;Aspect and Discourse in African Languages&amp;rdquo; at the 46th Annual Meeting of the Societas Linguistica Europaea, Split University Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>u̱t-Ma&#39;in verb research</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/u%CC%B1t-main-verb-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 09:30:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/u%CC%B1t-main-verb-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data for this project was collected in collaboration with local speakers. Nine texts were transcribed, glossed, translated and annotated. I then investigated the distribution of verb forms and the discourse function of those verb forms in U̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in narratives. In focus was the use of what I call the “Bare Verb” form for both present/habitual functions and for past time interpretation within the main event line of a narrative discourse. The function of the Bare Verb form is one of interpretive dependence on the discourse context. In this respect the Bare Verb form is similar to some of functions of the null verb form described for Wolof (Atlantic). Due to its textual interpretive dependence, the U̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in Bare Verb form never occurs as the first verb of a narrative event sequence, though the clauses it occurs in have all other components of finite main clause syntax (and the Bare Verb can clearly occur independently as the single verb form in a stand-alone utterance). The Bare Verb form is not a case of a grammatical form specifically devoted to narrative sequence; but the U̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in language does use sequenced Bare Verb forms as a strategy to further the narrative without need to reset the temporal, aspectual, or mood scenario for the listener (as well as other functions).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantics of u̱t-Ma&#39;in noun classes</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2012-semantics-of-utmain-noun-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 09:23:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2012-semantics-of-utmain-noun-classes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;: Paterson, Rebecca D. 2012. Semantics of U̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in noun classes. In Roger Blench and Stuart McGill (eds.). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.koeppe.de/titel_advances-in-minority-language-research-in-nigeria-vol-i&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Advances in minority language research in Nigeria&lt;/a&gt;, volume 1, 239-272. Köln: Rüdiger Köppe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIL Americas Area Professional Development Platform</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/sil-ama-professional-development-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 09:30:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/sil-ama-professional-development-platform/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mòoré Research</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/m%C3%B2or%C3%A9-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 09:30:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/m%C3%B2or%C3%A9-research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipero Research</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/pipero-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 09:30:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/pipero-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working alongside members of the Pero community from the two principal towns, Gwandum and Filiya, we reviewed previously published linguistic descriptions (1980s) and translated materials (1930s). Their goals included identifying areas for improving the orthography, developing a writing system for the contemporary language, testing that orthography in the community, and translating materials into the Pipero language. We produced a trial version of a transitional literacy book that allowed Pipero speakers who are already literate in Hausa or English to learn the proposed Pipero orthography. We also produced several booklets that were tested by the speaker/translators in their communities. The project continued after my involvement (which ended in 2007) and they have since translated the Gospel of Luke from the Christian New Testament and the&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>u̱t-Ma&#39;in noun research</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/u%CC%B1t-main-noun-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 09:30:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/project/u%CC%B1t-main-noun-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ut-Ma&amp;rsquo;in language is characterized by a complex noun classification system and a robust agreement system that permeates the language. While an understanding of the noun classes is essential to an understanding of the language as a whole, discussion includes the division of nouns into fourteen distinct classes, marked by prefixes on the nouns themselves and by agreement elements on other clause constituents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five of fourteen noun class prefixes are involved in nominalization of the verb; a nominalized verb, along with a goal complement or an object, can be incorporated into the nominalized phrase in the same way that a noun modifier is marked within a NP. These nominalized verb phrases are extensively used in auxiliary constructions that cover a diverse range of tense, aspect, and mode designations; the syntactic transitivity of the clause determines the morphosyntax used. Intransitive auxiliary constructions use the full range of nominalizing noun class marking; in contrast, transitive auxiliary constructions show a shift in their use of the noun class agreement morphology required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The noun class system of u̱t-Ma&#39;in, a West Kainji language of Northwestern Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/talk/2007-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 01:30:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/talk/2007-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;:  Smith, Rebecca Dow.  2007. &lt;em&gt;The noun class system of u̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in, a West Kainji language of Northwestern Nigeria&lt;/em&gt;. M.A. Thesis defense at the University of North Dakota.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on u̱t-Ma&#39;in noun classes</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/talk/2007-research-on-umain-noun-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/talk/2007-research-on-umain-noun-classes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smith, Rebecca Dow. 2007. &lt;em&gt;Research on u̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in noun classes&lt;/em&gt;. Presentation at Jos Linguistic Circle, Jos, Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The noun class system of U̱t-Ma&#39;in, a West Kainji language of Northwestern Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/workshops/2007-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2007 01:30:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/workshops/2007-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;:  Smith, Rebecca. D.  2007. The noun class system of U̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in, a West Kainji language of Northwestern Nigeria. MA thesis, University of North Dakota. Available online: &lt;a href=&#34;http://arts-sciences.und.edu/summer-institute-of-linguistics/theses/2007-smith-rebecca-d.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://arts-sciences.und.edu/summer-institute-of-linguistics/theses/2007-smith-rebecca-d.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The noun class system of u̱t-Ma&#39;in, a West Kainji language of Northwestern Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2007-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2007 01:30:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Becky-CV/publication/2007-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citeable as&lt;/strong&gt;:  Smith, Rebecca. D.  2007. The noun class system of u̱t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in, a West Kainji language of Northwestern Nigeria. M.A. Thesis, University of North Dakota. Available online: &lt;a href=&#34;http://arts-sciences.und.edu/summer-institute-of-linguistics/theses/2007-smith-rebecca-d.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://arts-sciences.und.edu/summer-institute-of-linguistics/theses/2007-smith-rebecca-d.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
