<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linguistics | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/linguistics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/linguistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Linguistics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 14:35:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Linguistics</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/linguistics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography of select papers on &#39;ethics&#39; and &#39;informed consent&#39; in Linguistic research</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/informed-consent-irb-biblography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 14:35:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/informed-consent-irb-biblography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short non-exhaustive bibliography of papers which discuss &lt;em&gt;Informed consent&lt;/em&gt; in the context of one or more of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minority language communities,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low literacy levels,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language research,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the legal aspect of the US IRB, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;how informed is informed consent&amp;rsquo; .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have several nagging questions, which I wonder how discussed they are including: &amp;ldquo;Is Intellectual property rights of minority language people covered in the typical informed consent protocols of language researchers?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How ethical is it to create voice-to-speech tools for a small language community when only one or two people provide voice samples?&amp;rdquo; When working independently, outside the confines of an organization these factors are not mitigated by institutional barriers to creativity or participant considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citations are kept in a GitHub gist. Comments are welcome via GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#34;application/javascript&#34; src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/HughP/b34e56efd7199bde727493f438a79f01.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2019-automatic-speech-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2019-automatic-speech-recognition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently I am working with easy-to-get speech data. This includes a language of Nepal, a language of Nigeria, and a language of Tanzania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools I use or have found interesting are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dmort27/epitran&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Epitran&lt;/a&gt; - A tool for transcribing orthographic text as IPA (International Phonetic Alphabet) &lt;!-- the team building it is working out of this doc: https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Z0pz22DXYw5CIp2Eo6ODbrTojqfq3e4jGjguZjbGqWE/edit#gid=1782468899 --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U̠t-Ma&#39;in Lexicography</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-lexicography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-lexicography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project includes combining and collating several U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in databases that Becky Paterson has created over the 12 years she has worked with the U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in language community. We are also importing as many Hausa terms as possible for specific elicitation (such as regional plants and animals). The final database includes grammatical features of individual lexemes. We are including various external analyses from phonology tools. None of this data is currently public. But when it is, a link from here will be posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OWL and the Rice Farmer</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-owl-and-the-rice-farmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 14:14:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-owl-and-the-rice-farmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent email I was asked by a &lt;em&gt;European Linguistic Professional SIL Colleague&lt;/em&gt; about the ease of use of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.mpi.nl/tla/elan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELAN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is ELAN easy enough to use, so that an Indonesian rice farmer can use it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am am a offended with the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; terminology which is prevalent in SIL discourse. However, to understand this term, and its usage I think it is important to understand another term used prior to &lt;em&gt;the rice farmer&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;em&gt;The Ordinary Working Linguist&lt;/em&gt;. This older phrase has gained some traction as evidenced by its adoption in the linguistic literature&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OWL&lt;/em&gt; or &amp;lsquo;ordinary working linguist&amp;rsquo; is attributed 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icsi.berkeley.edu/icsi/blog/chuck-fillmore-dies-at-84&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;by George Lakoff&lt;/a&gt; to Charles Fillmore as a self-describing term. Though it is impossible to say if Fillmore actually coined the term. If he did then it is an interesting frame by the discoverer of cognitive framing. I have yet to meet an &lt;em&gt;ordinary linguist&lt;/em&gt;. I have met smart linguists, extraordinary linguists, novel linguists, quirky linguists, geeky linguists, and ornery linguists — but never an &lt;em&gt;ordinary one&lt;/em&gt;. The second issue I take with this contrived frame is that it suggest that somewhere there might be a &lt;em&gt;non-working linguist&lt;/em&gt;. Now, either I have never met a lazy linguist, or I have been foiled by some collective endeavor. That is, the linguists I have met have somehow &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; decided that I am an extremely boring person — the kind to be avoided, and &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; have feign busyness! Granted busyness is not the same as &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; but I have never met a linguist who is not engaged in some sort of activity which has a mistakable similitude to &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the same, the notion of &amp;ldquo;OWL&amp;rdquo; seems to be very useful to a large group of linguists. For instance, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholars.sil.org/gary_f_simons/preprint/computing_environment&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gary F. Simons suggests&lt;/a&gt; that Helen Aristar Dry proposed a book in the early 1990s with the title &lt;em&gt;Computers and the Ordinary Working Linguist.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, While David Nathan, Peter Austin, Andrew Black, Piotr Bański, Mike Cahill, Jeff Good, Steven Moran, Scott Farrar, and René van den Berg all use the term in their works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In honor of Fillmore, if we take a framing view of the phrase &amp;ldquo;ordinary working linguist&amp;rdquo; we can see that many of the authors are discussing the concept within the frame of linguistic computing — the computer tools that linguists use to do their work. However, it can be argued that there is an SIL specific shift in the framing of the phrase (usage by Cahill, Schroeder, Simons, Black, and van den Berg). Van den Berg&amp;rsquo;s use is most articulate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the typical SIL fieldworker is what has been called an ‘owl’, that is, an ‘ordinary working linguist’ who has been given enough training to enable him or her to do the job; this  is usually a minimum of  two semesters of field linguistics at graduate level. A typical SIL field worker is therefore very  much a generalist, without specialist knowledge in any branch of linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van den Berg&amp;rsquo;s usage is both confirmed and then contrasted by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20130308204655/https://www.sil.org/linguistics/people&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIL International&lt;/a&gt; on its website where it contrasts the term with &lt;em&gt;Linguistics Coordinators&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Linguistics Consultants&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;International Linguistics Advisors&lt;/em&gt;. It is clear to see that within the shared frame by SIL staff, that Linguistic Consultants are those who have more training than typical SIL field workers. For several reasons, including reduced staffing, and paradigm shifts within project management related moral ownership within the tasks of language development, SIL has moved from ex-pat driven projects to nationally staffed and ethnolinguistic community driven projects. SIL&amp;rsquo;s minimally trained &amp;ldquo;OWLs&amp;rdquo; moved up the organizational chart to become project managers/facilitators, leaving open the &amp;ldquo;bottom&amp;rdquo; of the chart, ergo the new need for &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; as a newly perceived class of computer user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the term &lt;em&gt;rice farmer&lt;/em&gt; 14 times in the internal SIL International wiki and I find &amp;ldquo;OWL&amp;rdquo; 83 times. These terms surface mostly among SIL computer app developers, but I also hear them used by SIL policy and procedures developers, SIL program planners, and SIL educators. To me this term comes off as a class distinction term (and maybe there is nothing wrong with class distinction; I mean the Jews had class distinctions at the time of Jesus, the Cretans had classes at the time of Titus, the British have it, and castes are alive and well in India, etc.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). However, as I find the term being used in SIL, a more transparent term might be &amp;lsquo;low socio-economic and low educational &lt;em&gt;capacity&lt;/em&gt; individual&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that in my work with Steve Marlett in Mexico, I worked with ethnolinguistic moronity language users who were not &amp;lsquo;low educational capacity individuals&amp;rsquo; rather they were high educational capacity individuals. When I went to Malaysia and worked with Sean Conklin, the same thing, ethnolinguistic minority language users were not low educational capacity individuals. When I went to Nigeria and worked with people like Becky Paterson and David Rowbory, the people doing language work with us were not low educational capacity individuals. In fact the Nigerian rice farmer/pastor/student/translator/cultural guide/language activist who was on our language project team can and does use ELAN after some training (and uses Facebook without training to boot — FYI: I need training on ELAN too!). So, why then do SIL staff use terms like &amp;lsquo;rice farmers&amp;rsquo; when they talk about designing software for users? Something seems to be wrong with this picture. My guess is that there is a real reason why SIL staff use the term, but it is not the reason that SIL staff attribute as the causation of the observation of &amp;ldquo;low educational capacity individuals&amp;rdquo; - as we observe dark skinned colleagues who try and use SIL software and don&amp;rsquo;t intuitively know how to use the tools. My guess is that the reason for the use of the term is because it is part of the SIL corporate ethos. SIL staff use (or at least have in the past) their educational courses at various SIL training events as filters to find the &amp;lsquo;best and brightest students&amp;rsquo; and recommend those for various field service within SIL. Then in the advanced classes SIL staff obfuscate the materials just to make them harder, to see if those same students are able to still keep up. So, as I see it, there seems to be this undefined class difference in SIL&amp;rsquo;s corporate sociology preferring those who can distill obfuscated communications under stress and dis-preferring those who cannot distill obfuscated signals under stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the following four reasons I strongly dis-prefer the terms &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;OWL&amp;rsquo; as they often appear in SIL discourse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; terminology is actually very useful for professional reasons. Software design is about communicating. It is about communicating relational concepts in a visual context. It is about connecting new analogies with salient concepts. User Interface (UI - what a software user sees and interacts with) is the gateway to User Experience (UX - the emotional, logical, task based context of activities that are attempting to be facilitated by the software designer and accomplished by the software user). Therefore what UX is really about is communicating ideas and creating positive and successful interactions. If the UI fails to create the designed UX then it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the user is a rice farmer or a Ph.D. candidate from an Australian university. The end result is that the user is frustrated and will not use the software willingly. Therefore, singling out the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; from the white guy is not really a useful construct because all users, whether black, white, tan, farmer, or stockbroker, are subject to the same constraints and frustrations of software which is not intuitively implemented. It is my experience that programmers (not just SIL programmers) usually do not intuitively know how application users think or behave. UX design is an art and a science that takes experimentation and a solid grasp of information design principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget that, at least in software design we are talking about the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; with a computer, an iPad, or an android device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We never use the American Corn Farmer, or the Norwegian Reindeer Rancher as analogies, and I am a bit tired of singling out people from tropical areas because their skin is darker, or their average height is shorter, or because they grow rice in their backyard. The focus on the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; does not help us deal with the white guy&amp;rsquo;s problem with the software and robs us of a balanced view of the real communication challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the term &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; seems to put the ethnolinguistic minority language users and nationals in a sub-standard class relative to &amp;lsquo;real linguists&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;real missionaries&amp;rsquo;. Yes, my African colleagues who do have their own farms and families, also use SIL software; I first drove a tractor at age 13 and grew up on a farm, so what is the difference? By making the &amp;lsquo;OWL&amp;rsquo; or the &amp;lsquo;rice farmer&amp;rsquo; as some uninitiated or limited capacity person,  the &amp;ldquo;reason&amp;rdquo; for new design (i.e the reason that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://software.sil.org/wesay&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WeSay&lt;/a&gt; was created to work with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://software.sil.org/fieldworks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FLEx&lt;/a&gt;) doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve the fact that even for highly-educated-white-professionals FLEx is still confusing. The issue is a communications issue not a smarts or intelligence issue. Linguistic concepts can be communicated about beautifully and communicated simply, both in the classroom and in software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this post motivates those in SIL to take a deeper look at User Experience issues in the software tools and websites we build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bański, Piotr. 2010. Why TEI stand-off annotation doesn’t quite work: and why you might want to use it nevertheless. In Proceedings of Balisage: The Markup Conference 2010 (Balisage Series on Markup Technologies 5), n.p. Montréal, Canada: Balisage. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4242/BalisageVol5.Banski01&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4242/BalisageVol5.Banski01&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;van den Berg, René. 2013. SIL and its contribution to Oceanic linguistics. Language and Linguistics in Oceania 5. 33–74. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.izumi-syuppan.co.jp/LLO_PDF/vol_05/13Berg.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.izumi-syuppan.co.jp/LLO_PDF/vol_05/13Berg.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black, H Andrew &amp;amp; Gary F Simons. 2008. The SIL Fieldworks Language Explorer Approach to Morphological Parsing. In Nick Gaylord, Alexis Palmer &amp;amp; Elias Ponvert (eds.), Texas Linguistics Society 10: Computational Linguistics for Less-Studied Languages, 37–55. Stanford, California: CSLI Publications. &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.stanford.edu/group/cslipublications/cslipublications/TLS/TLS10-2006/TLSX-2006-toc.shtml&#34;&gt;http://web.stanford.edu/group/cslipublications/cslipublications/TLS/TLS10-2006/TLSX-2006-toc.shtml&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cahill, Mike C. 2001. Farewell from the Coordinator. Notes on Linguistics 4(4). 203–204. &lt;a href=&#34;https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED467733.pdf&#34;&gt;https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED467733.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farrar, Scott &amp;amp; Steven Moran. 2008. The e-Linguistics toolkit. In Workshop in the 4th IEEE International Conference on e-Science, Indianapolis, Indiana, 10 December 2008, n.p. IEEE Computer Society. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5167/UZH-84686&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5167/UZH-84686&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good, Jeff. 2010. Valuing technology: Finding the linguist’s place in a new technological universe. In Lenore A. Grenoble &amp;amp; N. Louanna Furbee (eds.), Language Documentation: Practice and values, 111–132. Amsterdam: John Benjamins Publishing Company. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1075/z.158.13goo&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1075/z.158.13goo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan, David &amp;amp; Peter K Austin. 2004. Reconceiving metadata: language documentation through thick and thin. Language Documentation and Description 2. 179–188. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/029&#34;&gt;http://www.elpublishing.org/PID/029&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schroeder, Leila. 2008. Bantu Orthography Manual (SIL E-Books 9). Revised 2010. Dallas, Texas: SIL International. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sil.org/resources/archives/9241&#34;&gt;https://www.sil.org/resources/archives/9241&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which would be later published as: Aristar Dry, Helen &amp;amp; John Lawler (eds.). 1998. Using Computers in Linguistics: A Practical Guide. 1st edn. London: Routledge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203059012&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203059012&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States doesn&amp;rsquo;t have classes, only more successful capitalists and less successful capitalists. — ⟨snark⟩ &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geo-Linguistics</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-geo-linguistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-geo-linguistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are seven major sub-areas of this project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explaining cartographic concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explaining and reviewing tools for generating and processing the necessay data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating population density visualizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collecting place names and generating a map in Nigeria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a map of the language documentation files in the Meꞌphaa language documentation project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a map of the language documentation files in the U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in language documentation project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating several maps for Dan related to my M.A. thesis work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;!-- Map making tools

Import geo-names into QGIS: http://forum.geonames.org/gforum/posts/list/67.page
QGIS to illustrator: https://vimeo.com/124793295
Georeferencing Topo Sheets and Scanned Maps: http://www.qgistutorials.com/en/docs/georeferencing_basics.html

https://mygeodata.cloud/converter/svg-to-kml
https://bitbucket.org/tbrugz/kmlutils/wiki/HOWTO.en
https://freegeographytools.com/2009/convertreproject-shapefiles-and-kml-files-to-svg-format-with-indiemapper

https://bitbucket.org/voron-raven/maps

Filter country shapes: https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Osmfilter --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-Mexico/File-man.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hugh in recording&#34;&gt;
Grammarian of digital file names is the loneliest job of them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mexico.sil.org/publications/i-wpindex/work_papers_-_mephaa_grammar_files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Corpus of descriptive work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;File-man.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hugh in recording&#34;&gt;
Grammarian of digital file names is the loneliest job of them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mexico.sil.org/publications/i-wpindex/work_papers_-_mephaa_grammar_files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Corpus of descriptive work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdental approximant</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-interdental-approximant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 08:18:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-interdental-approximant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research project was spearheaded by Ken Olson. As a collaborator with him I focused on the historical linguistics status of the interdental approximant in Philippine languages. I also did a lot of library resources discovery and acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project description I have listed more than my contribution because I am not sure there is anywhere else that has pulled together the combined research on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results &amp;amp; Significance&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultrasound Study on the articulation of the interdental approximant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published phonetic descriptions of the interdental approximant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic Output&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publications&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mielke, Jeff, Kenneth S. Olson, Adam Baker &amp;amp; Diana Archangeli. 2011. Articulation of the Kagayanen interdental approximant: An ultrasound study. Journal of Phonetics 39(3). 403–412. DOI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.wocn.2011.02.008&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1016/j.wocn.2011.02.008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olson, Kenneth S., Emy T. Ballenas &amp;amp; Nilo M. Borromeo. 2009. Buhi’non (Bikol) digital wordlist: Presentation form. Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation 3(2). 213–225. URI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/4440&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/4440&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olson, Kenneth S., Glenn Machlan &amp;amp; Nelson Amangao. 2008. Minangali (Kalinga) digital wordlist: Presentation form. Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation 2(1). 141–156. URI 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/1772&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://hdl.handle.net/10125/1772&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olson, Kenneth S. &amp;amp; Jeff Mielke. 2008. Acoustic properties of the interdental approximant in Kagayanen. Journal of the Acoustical Society of America 123(5). 3460. DOI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2934307&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1121/1.2934307&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Academic Work&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew Harley (2012) Unusual sounds in Nigerian languages. In Advances in Minority Language Research in Nigeria Part I (eds.) Roger M. Blench and Stuart McGill. Kay Williamson Educational Foundation African languages Monographs No. 5. pages: 38-65. Rüdiger Köppe Verlag: Köln&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow-up work&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that the interdental approximant [ð̞] in Austronesian languages should challenge linguists in three important areas and thus deserves more thought and perhaps application in our theories. These categories are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The phonological status and interactions that happen with the segment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The phonetic contrast of the segment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Historical status of the segment and the impact of its recognition in the Austronesian historical linguistic narrative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications to date have focused on two relevant aspects of the interdental approximant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ð̞ is important in descriptive linguistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ð̞ is different phonetically from other described segments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following remain to be shown clearly in appropriate publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phonetic contrast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the duration of the sound and what are the boarders?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure the stable section?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where does it stop and where does it begin?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the acoustical (in terms of both production and perception) difference between /l/ and /ð̞ /?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ulturasound study does provide a good starting point to answer these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ it has a unique spectrograph when compared with other liquids, vowels, and interdentals - especially within the same language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is different from the native sounds of { l, a, ɐ, n, ʔ, d, g, r, s, h, x} which occur in Philippine languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This has been done in small phonology descriptions but not full scale acoustically reference-able phonetic descriptions across the entire set of languages discussed in the &lt;em&gt;JIPA&lt;/em&gt; article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is different from the borrowed sounds of { l, a, ɐ, n, ʔ, d, g, θ, ð, r, s, h, x, ɣ}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of psycholinguistics the question remains,: &lt;em&gt;What are the unique properties of this sound as they are culturally defined?&lt;/em&gt; or to put this another way: &lt;em&gt;What are the acustic cues, what are the visual cues, and what are the cultural constraints that those cues may violate?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research position suggests that there has been change. Change involves a variety of cognitive processes. Re-analysis is one such process. If I hypothesize that re-analysis has occurred, then what is the Cognitive load of this segment? How has that load shifted or why can it shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the unique properties that users attribute to this segment as cross-linguistically defined (but keeping within Austronesian or the Austro-Tai hypotheses).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are those unique properties as Universally or empirically defined?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Historical Narrative&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an open question with relationship to historical Austronesian as to what the metrical structure of the language was. If we posit some change in the metical structrue what relevance does that have on the interdental approximant? Does the concept of Phonetic Gemination apply?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some theories of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austro-Tai_languages&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Austro-Tai&lt;/a&gt; there is some relevance to constructing suprasegmental features and genisis or de-genesis processes for these features. In that contexts: &lt;em&gt;Is it possible that ð̞ is a tone bearing unit? (TBU)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interdental is contrastive with dental in Place in the IPA Chart
ð̞ is important to PAn Historical Phonology Theory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is related to several mergers and splits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is PAn *R&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ Shows that [+Nasal], historically, is, or is/and a super-segmental feature in Austronesian languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ shows that there are fewer proto-phonemes than necessary in current models
of PAn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ helps us to understand the PAn foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ was represented in the baybin original orthography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ is relevant enough to be represented consistently in orthographies in the
languages it occurs in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phonology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several open phonological questions. Some of these have answers in the cited materials, but the data is not always clear for all languages which also have interdental approximants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the claimed Phonemes of kangayen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be all the more the claim that ð̞ is phonemic not due to a split. If it is a retention then this perspective has more weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the ð̞ pattern concerning natural classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a feature geometry perspective, what features does ð̞ have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Austornesian language have Metathesis. Is this metathesis process triggered in any way by the ð̞?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ð̞ has moraic value - what is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the affect of ð̞ on vowel quality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways can we measure the impact that ð̞ has on cognitive load?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the ð̞ occur in multiple areas of the lexicon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this a survey of the texts should be used to evaluated the
location of ð̞ in the lexicon. One resource for texts could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grayden, Bruce. 1978. &amp;ldquo;Southern Kalinga [language text].&amp;rdquo; In Evan L. Antworth (ed.),
Folktale texts, 13-23. Studies in Philippine Linguistics, 2(2). Manila: Linguistic Society of the Philippines and Summer Institute of Linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I want to research?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I want to research it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the Problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the Solution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I want to Say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the continued importance of a feature analysis to the field of descriptive linguistics and to the field of historical linguistics and to the field of Phonology?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
