<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/open-source/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Open Source</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 14:14:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Open Source</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/open-source/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Awesome List for Open Source Software</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/an-awesome-list-for-open-source-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 14:14:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/an-awesome-list-for-open-source-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The world is full of problems. Some of these can be solved through the use of technology. Other problems can&amp;rsquo;t be solved directly through the use of technology, but the deployment of technologies can impact social environments and social interactions in a way so that the problems not solvable directly though technology can be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low-resource languages suffer from one of the problems of the second type. That is there is a sociological problem that follows briefly in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel-good, and do-good linguists often want to help &amp;ldquo;low-resourced&amp;rdquo; language community have digital tools in their language. This scenario is mirrored by the a different scenario, which may be contrasted with people &amp;ldquo;helping&amp;rdquo; from the outside. That is,people from within the low-resource language want to create tools for using their language - often in written form - in digital contexts. The result is that there are often a set of persons who are project managers, or who hold the business strings (access to grant funding, and are responsible for contracting with technologists to implement the project ideas and goals). The problem that occurs is that the more project managers there are (which might be more than one per language - with over 7,000 languages) the more divergent the technological solutions which are expensive and often not compatible or extensible - even if they are &amp;ldquo;open sourced&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problem we are trying to solve is the communication problem between the plethora of coders which vary from cowboy soloists to dedicated shops working on language software targeted for use in Low-resourced communities, and the growing number of visionary project managers, who might have a background in linguistics, but often not have one in information technology or in information technology project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of collaboration, and reusability of code are obvious. However, there still stand a large gap between the project manager and the coding technologist. We find that this gap can be characterized by two critical problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the things which have been coded - and for what purpose are they coded?
Assuming that this data can be gathered, how can this data be quirky made usable so that project managers can use the information intelligently in their evolving relationships with their technical teams? In summary we must create a pile of data, and then we need to make it usable.
In the spirit of taking baby steps, we have started to amass a pile of data (asking the question - what do we know has been coded), we have started with a solution which is more native to coders than to project managers. We have used an element of Github culture - &amp;lsquo;the Awesome list&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this does list does make a browse able list, it does not address the myriad of points of view which project managers come from. Synthesizing the data to match the various points of view; making the data relevant and usable is still an open task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Educational Resources OER Links</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/open-educational-resources-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 14:35:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/open-educational-resources-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks a go I put together a resource (&amp;ldquo;whitepaper&amp;rdquo;) outlining an economic strategy related to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_educational_resources&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Educational Resources (OER)&lt;/a&gt; and mobile compatible resources. The purpose was to kickstart and provide ideas for the organization I work for to consider alternative models of information maintenance and dissemination. The following links are more or less my list of references which did not make into that paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economically (in terms of information economy), the problem I see with 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corestandards.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CommonCore&lt;/a&gt; as it is implemented in the USA across grades 1-12, is that law and policy affect the kinds of resources being produced and subsequently also shared in these curriculum development co-op endeavors (OER). I think the impact is greater than originally anticipated (or perhaps not, perhaps this is a foreign policy move affecting exports of knowledge). The indirect impact of CommonCore on the consumers of these OER materials, is that when people from other countries consume Open Education Resources, they are consuming CommonCore. Thankfully, there is a lot of OER work going on at the university level and outside of the scope of CommonCore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also to note: OER works well with some subjects in which there is very little change; like science (chemistry and physics) or math. There is so much ground to cover in these subjects that OER makes sense. However, for subjects like linguistics, where models are proposed all the time, and subsequently challenged, it is harder to produce an OER resource with a lot of buy-in among educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;general&#34;&gt;General&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ocw.mit.edu/index.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&amp;rsquo;s Open courses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;%22http://www.opensourcetext.org/&#34;&gt;California&amp;rsquo;s Open Textbook Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ck12.org/student/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ck-12 open learning platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merlot.org/merlot/index.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Merlot II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://concord.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Concord Consortium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oerafrica.org/OERInitiativesinAfrica/tabid/296/Default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OER focusing on Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-textbooks&#34;&gt;Digital Textbooks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://serc.carleton.edu/serc/EOS-87-31-2006.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reconsidering the Textbook&lt;/a&gt;: Bierman, P., C. Massey, and C. Manduca (2006), Reconsidering the Textbook, Eos Trans. AGU, 87(31), 306.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://concord.org/blog/flexible-textbooks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Flexible Textbooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-linguistics-resources&#34;&gt;Open Linguistics Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Introduction_to_Linguistics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Introduction to Linguistics Textbook on Wikibooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding-models&#34;&gt;Funding Models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://p2pfoundation.net/Funding_Models_for_Open_Educational_Resources&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Funding Models for Open Educational Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;semantic-search-and-oer-discoverability&#34;&gt;Semantic Search and OER Discoverability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meas-extension.org/oer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Design to Share&lt;/a&gt;:  by Gwyn Shelle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Organizing Knowledge in Meaningful Ways Enhances Search and Supports Independent Learning &lt;a href=&#34;http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007%2F978-3-642-24731-6_33&#34; &gt;Book Chapter&lt;/a&gt; in Metadata and Semantic Research, Communications in Computer and Information Science Volume 240, 2011, pp. 324-336.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



  
  
  

&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-image-adapted-from-lumen-learning-2014-slide-show-presentation-open-education-in-the-most-pilot-program&#34;itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/open-educational-resources-links/featured_hu81bc1a06ad23d1a3394f8e66fdd45308_40173_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Image adapted from Lumen Learning. (2014). Slide Show Presentation Open Education in the MOST Pilot Program.&#34;&gt;

  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/open-educational-resources-links/featured_hu81bc1a06ad23d1a3394f8e66fdd45308_40173_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1215&#34; height=&#34;575&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Image adapted from Lumen Learning. (2014). Slide Show Presentation Open Education in the MOST Pilot Program.
      
&lt;span class=&#34;img-attribution&#34;&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lumenlearning.com&#34;&gt; Lumen Learning&lt;span itemprop=&#34;creator&#34; itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34; itemscope&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;name&#34; content=&#34;Lumen Learning&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
