<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SIL International | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/sil-international/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/sil-international/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>SIL International</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:14:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>SIL International</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/institutions/sil-international/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website License vs. Content License</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/website-license-vs-content-license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:14:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/website-license-vs-content-license/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When considering internet publishing attribution and proper licensing is very important. One important context to make clear is the distinction between the HTML and visual presentation/content layer of a website, the code of a website, and any downloadable objects in a website such as PDFs. Today I was looking at the &lt;em&gt;Rapid Words&lt;/em&gt; website. &lt;em&gt;Rapid Words&lt;/em&gt; is an SIL product and methodology which facilitates a multi-party conversation to quickly discover many words in a language. SIL developed a specific website to promote this methodology and its associated downloadable content. As I review the website, I am wondering several things about the licenses advertised on the RapidWords site. The web-page I am looking at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rapidwords.net/resources/files/rwc-questionnaire&#34;&gt;http://www.rapidwords.net/resources/files/rwc-questionnaire&lt;/a&gt; Screen shots are presented here for ease of access (and permanence).&lt;/p&gt;








  



  
  
















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-bottom-of-page&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/website-license-vs-content-license/Bottom-of-page_hu6da07655c86f6ebcd4582582f273570d_233266_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Bottom of Page&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/website-license-vs-content-license/Bottom-of-page_hu6da07655c86f6ebcd4582582f273570d_233266_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;Image of webpage footer&#34; width=&#34;1920&#34; height=&#34;1080&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bottom of Page
      
&lt;span class=&#34;img-attribution&#34;&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rapidwords.net/resources/files/rwc-questionnaire&#34;&gt; 
rapidwords.net (SIL International)
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;









  



  
  
















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-bottom-of-page&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/website-license-vs-content-license/Top-of-page_hu92947ba777579ad27f0550a26096e373_491839_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Bottom of Page&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/website-license-vs-content-license/Top-of-page_hu92947ba777579ad27f0550a26096e373_491839_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;Image of webpage footer&#34; width=&#34;1920&#34; height=&#34;1080&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bottom of Page
      
&lt;span class=&#34;img-attribution&#34;&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rapidwords.net/resources/files/rwc-questionnaire&#34;&gt; 
rapidwords.net (SIL International)
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the footer, I see a copyright statement and then a CC-BY-SA license. Many websites who choose to put copyright and license material in the footer are really only referencing the Theme files of their web-page, or the immediately on-screen content. This is very common for open-source themes for WordPress, Drupal, and Joomla. It is unclear to me if this is the case on the RapidWords website. Or is the footer referring to the entire content of the website inclusive of the downloadable content? If it is referring to the theme files, then they ought to be licensed as code not as a creative work according to the Creative Commons Foundation. (The Creative Commons Foundation recommends not using Creative Commons Licenses for code base projects and points to other more appropriate licenses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I go the content of the web-page link above (see screens shot), there is a CC license field in the middel of the page. This field is empty and in lieu of a license, I find a copyright statement saying all &amp;ldquo;rights are reserved&amp;rdquo;. So which is it? CC-BY-SA or All rights reserved?&lt;/p&gt;








  



  
  
















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-close-up-of-screen-content&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/website-license-vs-content-license/decalkfgkndojdgc_huf9c93931f5b10e522981e6221644a41f_12481_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Close-up of screen content&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/website-license-vs-content-license/decalkfgkndojdgc_huf9c93931f5b10e522981e6221644a41f_12481_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;Close-up of screen content&#34; width=&#34;518&#34; height=&#34;211&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Close-up of screen content
      
&lt;span class=&#34;img-attribution&#34;&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rapidwords.net/resources/files/rwc-questionnaire&#34;&gt; 
rapidwords.net (SIL International)
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then when I download the PDF of the content via the PDF button provided the content of the PDF only contains the copyright statement not the CC-BY-SA statement. Further adding confusion because the website is offering a PDF to me but then saying that the PDF is &amp;ldquo;all rights reserved&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, when one downloads the resources under the resource section the resources do not have a license statement in them (I would have expected a copyright and a license statement in the footer of each printable page in the downloaded document).
Because there is a footer on the web-page with a CC license, is the website user to assume that these download able resources are CC-BY-SA?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizations can avoid sending mixed messages to their constituency by clearly marking who is the copyright holder, on websites &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the content those websites contain. Organizational policies related to web-publishing should include editorial checks for these sorts of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SIL Archive and its Two Sided Markets</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-sil-archive-and-its-two-sided-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 01:41:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-sil-archive-and-its-two-sided-markets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about the language data marketplace (exchange if one prefers), and the role of archives in a world where minority language speakers are also internet users and digital file consumers. In particular I have been thinking about 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sil.org/resources/language-culture-archives&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SIL’s Language and Culture Archive&lt;/a&gt; and the economic model called a 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Two-sided_market&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;two sided market&lt;/a&gt;. So, SIL as “Partners in Language Development” seems to be well situated for analysis using the two sided market analysis (matching linguist and professionals with language development skills, and persons with language development skills with interested parties in developing their language). On the surface, it seems that the SIL archive would also benefit from being the center of exchange between these same two groups. This is the subject of one of my slides for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2013-challenges-ramp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;an upcoming presentation&lt;/a&gt;, therefore I sketched out the interactions various SIL staff might have with the archive to see if I could diagram the social interactions around language data in SIL’s two sided market. To my surprise, the two sided nature of access to data in the archive is not supported, thereby blocking a data-centric archiving service. It makes me wonder what the perceived value of the archive really is, and if the perceived value is low, then why bother? What is the return on investment (ROI) for users on either side of the market?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to summarize the relationships between the various clients of the archive in the following image.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/the-sil-archive-and-its-two-sided-markets/SIL-Archive-and-its-two-sided-markets.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SIL Archive and its two multi-sided market representation&#34; title=&#34;SIL Archive and its two multi-sided market representation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Literacy vs. Literacy in a Digital Medium</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/digital-literacy-vs-literacy-in-a-digital-medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 14:35:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/digital-literacy-vs-literacy-in-a-digital-medium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While working on a description of the Eastern Dan writing system I found it challenging to keep track of all the different writing system evolutions and the various materials produced in each writing system. As I listen to the challenges faced in various linguistic projects (archiving, OCR, language revitalization, corpus creation) around the world, which work with written linguistic materials I find that they also often have the same basic problems. That is, the same language may be written with different transcription systems. There is currently no clear and concise way to create an identifier for language transcription systems. Some have turned to the ISO 639-3 to say &amp;ldquo;the writing system of &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; language&amp;rdquo;, however this is often not descriptive enough. The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/rfc/bcp/bcp47&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BCP47 identifier&lt;/a&gt; is much more descriptive and useful in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the term writing system rather than orthography because orthography is narrowly construed in technological contexts. That is, &lt;em&gt;orthography&lt;/em&gt; applies to spelling, while &lt;em&gt;writing system&lt;/em&gt; applies to the characters used to communicate in a given language 








. Sometimes a writing system revision implies or necessitates an orthography change, sometimes it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. When an orthography change adds or removes a character (Unicode character) from the language it also implies a writing system change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These relationships are illustrated in the following graph replicated from 








.&lt;/p&gt;

























&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;constable2003.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;constable2003.png&#34; alt=&#34;Orthography and writing system relationship diagram&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example the following languages and their writing system histories demonstrate some of the complexities which a catalog of writing system evolutions would need to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tarok&#34;&gt;Tarok&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tarok orthography falls in the category of an SIL revision in 1976 of a missionary orthography first produced in 1919. Tarok people did a comprehensive revision in 2018, covering alphabets and rules of the writing system. Tarok  [ISO 639-3: yer] is spoken Central Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dan&#34;&gt;Dan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan is a language of Liberia and the Ivory coast [ISO 639-3: dnj]. It requires three BCP47 codes to distinguish the language-writing system combinations, because there are three writing systems one in Liberia, one for Eastern Dan, one for Western Dan. Historically, Dan-Kla [ISO 639-3: lda] now recognized as a separate language, was also lumped in with Dan, the ISO 639-3 registrar addressed this in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;eastern-dan&#34;&gt;Eastern Dan&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the Dan example Eastern Dan has a history of 5 writing system versions, some with SIL involvement, some without. These are writing system revisions, not orthography revisions because the glyphs used in each case were different. It wasn’t just the spelling system that changed, it what the character repertoire needed to write the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mephaa&#34;&gt;Me&amp;rsquo;phaa&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me&amp;rsquo;phaa is a set of 4 ISO 639-3 languages but the Mexican government acknowledges something like 7 unique languages. They all share one writing system but spell words how they pronounce them in their respective regions. This means that there is one writing system, but several orthographies. As far as I know no orthography is standardized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;german&#34;&gt;German&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four countries, various different writing systems (glyphs), countries have discrete version histories, but conceded that they have one language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tem&#34;&gt;Tem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A language which uses both Ajami and Latin scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these kinds of issues in mind, I crafted the following fictitious statement which exemplifies some of the things for which a good catalog of writing system versions would account.&lt;/p&gt;

























&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;Basic-Business-Metrics-in-Writing-System-Evolution-Management.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;Basic-Business-Metrics-in-Writing-System-Evolution-Management.png&#34; alt=&#34;Database Categories&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

  

  










Bibliography called, but no references



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EGIDS, SIL, and Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/egids-sil-and-language-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 01:41:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/egids-sil-and-language-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About two or three weeks ago Gary Simons and Paul Lewis co-presented on an Extension to Fishman’s Graded Intergenerational Disruption Scale 







&lt;span class=&#34;hugo-cite-intext&#34;
        itemprop=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;#ucyjs36s&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;visually-hidden&#34;&gt;Citation: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34;&gt;&lt;meta itemprop=&#34;givenName&#34; content=&#34;M Paul&#34;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;familyName&#34;&gt;Lewis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;#32;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;datePublished&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)
    &lt;span class=&#34;hugo-cite-citation&#34;&gt;












&lt;span itemscope
      itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Article&#34;
      data-type=&#34;article&#34;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;familyName&#34;&gt;Lewis&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;#32;
    &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;givenName&#34; content=&#34;M Paul&#34; /&gt;
    M.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#32;&amp;amp;&amp;#32;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;familyName&#34;&gt;Simons&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;#32;
    &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;givenName&#34; content=&#34;Gary F&#34; /&gt;
    G.&lt;/span&gt;
  &amp;#32;
    (&lt;span itemprop=&#34;datePublished&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/span&gt;).
  &amp;#32;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Assessing Endangerment: Expanding Fishman’s Gids&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;i&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;about&#34;&gt;Revue roumaine de linguistique&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;#32;55(2)&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;#32;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;pagination&#34;&gt;103–120&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;#32;Retrieved from&amp;#32;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lingv.ro/RRL-2010.html&#34;
     itemprop=&#34;identifier&#34;
     itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/URL&#34;&gt;https://www.lingv.ro/RRL-2010.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;




&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
. Fishman’s scale for measuring Language Vitality and Language Endangerment has been around for about 2 decades (almost longer than me ;-)). The Ethnologue in its most recent version has started to list the position of the language on the EGIDS scale. This is something that the editors are looking to expand to all languages in the Ethnologue. This has some bearing on Language Documentation globally (as grant writers and funders look at EGIDS as a pivot point for language vitality) and because Language Documentation efforts usually (and typically) focus on languages on a 7 or higher on the scale (Shifting, Moribund, Nearly Extinct, etc). Whereas, SIL has largely focused its efforts on languages in a position of 0-6a on the EGIDS scale. (Which it makes sense from the perspective of the Bible Translation movement, where funders of Bible Translation projects are looking at the return on investment for their monies or funds are acquired for very specific tasks in language development work. It also makes sense in terms of managing the human resources of large volunteer organizations Wycliffe and SIL, which are involved in both the &lt;em&gt;Bible Translation Movement&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Language Development Movement&lt;/em&gt; – to optimize or economize the effort expended and to focus endeavors and services provided on languages with a higher language vitality [lower EGIDS score] seems a natural fit – languages with a higher EGIDS score are going to receive less Bible Translation dollars because it simply costs more. So herein lies the current conflict: &lt;em&gt;What is recognized as a priority for Language Documentation (stemming from the Endangered Language Movement) is not a priority for other kinds of projects in SIL&lt;/em&gt; – the kinds of projects which are funded through SIL’s partners like WycliffeUSA and fundraising campaigns like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20110618075555/http://wycliffe.org.uk/wycliffe/about/vision-2025.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Vision 2025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If SIL says that “yes” we will engage in language documentation, and says “We will directly engage language communities”; will SIL start where it already has Bible Translation projects? Or will it start with endangered languages as defined by the EGIDS? Funding as an interesting way of adjusting the way people see their priorities.
For pragmatic reasons it makes sense for SIL to start where it already has contacts and inroads to communities – even language documentation projects require successful relationships between linguists or language documentation program facilitators and community members. But this does not address how SIL will respond or create language development services for communities who speak languages on the EGIDS scale with a value of 7 or greater. This becomes a concern for SIL consultants and staff as they often have interests in or relationships with communities with an EGIDS score greater than 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As SIL moves from being an organization which has staff directly involved with activities in language communities, to becoming an organization which provides services to organizations working in communities there has been some discussion about SIL not being the solo organizational partner (where SIL partners directly with the community by sending an SIL staff person to live in the community) in any new start projects in language communities. This kind of strategy, shifts the responsibility for starting new projects to partner organizations and then shifts SIL responsibility to support them with services as it sees fit to provide. In terms of market place presence, this makes lots of sense for a services based company/organization/NGO. However, this also means that as the organization looks to change its involvement in the marketplace, that the market place will also respond and change. That is, the ways in which SIL used to be influential in both linguistics and language documentation, will change. SIL may still be a player but the other players in the larger marketplace of linguistics and language documentation (linguists and linguistic specialists both inside and outside SIL) will rely on SIL for linguistic expertise and data less (unless SIL can successfully provide a service which can offer linguistic expertise and linguistic data – which may be increasingly difficult to do provided the volunteerism basis of many SIL staff).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, this kind of EGIDS based decision making and finance steering might work well for focusing services and human resources efforts on Bible Translation projects but I do not see it working well with languages with an EGIDS score of 7 or greater. If SIL’s primary partners are evangelical partners, then on the large scale I do not see those partners as being interested in starting projects (particularly of the language documentation variety) in languages with an EGIDS value of 7 or greater, or the more endangered languages. This really then sets us up for the question: &lt;em&gt;In an SIL framework what is Language Documentation?&lt;/em&gt; (including: &lt;em&gt;How much documentation is sufficient for the purposes of the funding partners?&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;What can the documentation be used for?&lt;/em&gt;) This first question(s) should be followed with a question of the nature: &lt;em&gt;What does that mean for SIL and its operations (services) in other domains?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bibliography&#34;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

  

  










&lt;section class=&#34;hugo-cite-bibliography&#34;&gt;
  &lt;dl&gt;
    

      &lt;div id=&#34;ucyjs36s&#34;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;
          Lewis&amp;#32;&amp;amp;&amp;#32;Simons

          
          (2010)&lt;/dt&gt;

        &lt;dd&gt;
          












&lt;span itemscope
      itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Article&#34;
      data-type=&#34;article&#34;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;familyName&#34;&gt;Lewis&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;#32;
    &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;givenName&#34; content=&#34;M Paul&#34; /&gt;
    M.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#32;&amp;amp;&amp;#32;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;familyName&#34;&gt;Simons&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;#32;
    &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;givenName&#34; content=&#34;Gary F&#34; /&gt;
    G.&lt;/span&gt;
  &amp;#32;
    (&lt;span itemprop=&#34;datePublished&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/span&gt;).
  &amp;#32;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Assessing Endangerment: Expanding Fishman’s Gids&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;i&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;about&#34;&gt;Revue roumaine de linguistique&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;#32;55(2)&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;#32;&lt;span itemprop=&#34;pagination&#34;&gt;103–120&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;#32;Retrieved from&amp;#32;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lingv.ro/RRL-2010.html&#34;
     itemprop=&#34;identifier&#34;
     itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/URL&#34;&gt;https://www.lingv.ro/RRL-2010.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;




&lt;/dd&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
