<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resource Discovery | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/resource-discovery/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/resource-discovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Resource Discovery</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:35:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Resource Discovery</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/resource-discovery/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity and Typology Across OLAC Providers</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/diversity-and-typology-across-olac-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:35:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/diversity-and-typology-across-olac-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are all data providers to OLAC archives as some in the literature seem to imply, or are these implications an artifact of some other framing mechanism? In linguistics, framing is the establishment of a context under which a narrative is experienced. Lakoff and Filmore are both researchers in the concepts around framing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.language-archives.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Language Archives Community (OLAC)&lt;/a&gt; metadata profile is built on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dublincore.org/specifications/dublin-core/dcmi-terms&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dublin Core&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/openarchivesprotocol.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OAI&lt;/a&gt;. Essentially OLAC OAI feeds (to the OLAC aggregator) are modified (or &amp;ldquo;enhanced&amp;rdquo; using the XML attribute &lt;code&gt;xsi:type=&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;) OAI-PMH feeds. The OAI protocol was originally developed to be used by repository software to communicate with other repositories—in an effort to make a network of repositories. The OAI protocol works well as designed. The OLAC implementation of OAI inherits some of the OAI provided terms and concepts. When OLAC was first created, the profile was originally assumed to be describing archived language resources, and archives were assumed to be repositories—at least in the OAI sense. Many, including recent publications talk about &amp;ldquo;archives&amp;rdquo; providing records to the OLAC aggregator. These claims and references are interesting, confusing, and inaccurate—though if the sense of archive, is really and OAI repository, then I seen the connection. However, that is not what most people think of when they hear &lt;em&gt;language archive&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;archive&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The framing of terms from the OAI context is laid out in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/openarchivesprotocol.html#Introduction&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;introduction to the OAI-PMH standard&lt;/a&gt;. The following definitions are given. [^1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Providers&lt;/em&gt; administer systems that support the OAI-PMH as a means of exposing metadata; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service Providers&lt;/em&gt; use metadata harvested via the OAI-PMH as a basis for building value-added services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A &lt;em&gt;repository&lt;/em&gt; is a network accessible server that can process the 6 OAI-PMH requests in the manner described in this document.&lt;/strong&gt; A repository is managed by a data provider to expose metadata to harvesters. To allow various repository configurations, the OAI-PMH distinguishes between three distinct entities related to the metadata made accessible by the OAI-PMH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distinction here is that the corporate entity implementing data sharing technology is the &lt;em&gt;Data Provider&lt;/em&gt;. While the server technology implementing the access is call the &lt;em&gt;repository&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, within the OLAC documentation and academic literature presenting OLAC further conceptualization of terms occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of the term &amp;ldquo;archive&amp;rdquo; to mean all data providers to OLAC is  &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt; from a linguistic point of view because by calling &lt;em&gt;Data Providers&lt;/em&gt; (in the OAI sense) &amp;ldquo;archives&amp;rdquo; authors use the language of inclusion which maps well to the concepts of &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;community&amp;rdquo; which can be found in the OLAC name, but the language of inclusion here does not acknowledge the diversity of the kinds of data providers. While inclusion and an under representation of diversity are the impacts, there may be other factors as well. If we look at the OLAC documentation, the documentation in the examples and in the XML elements calls things &amp;ldquo;archives&amp;rdquo;. Consider the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.language-archives.org/OLAC/protocol.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OLAC Protocol&lt;/a&gt; which is an extension of the basic OAI-PMH protocol. Specifically, in 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.language-archives.org/OLAC/protocol.html#OLAC%20archive%20description&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;section 3&lt;/a&gt; where OLAC data providers are required to return a specific element when the OAI-PMH verb &lt;code&gt;Identify&lt;/code&gt; is used. The title of the XML element is &lt;code&gt;olac-archive&lt;/code&gt;.  It has two possible attribute values &lt;code&gt;personal&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;institutional&lt;/code&gt;. The example given is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;olac-archive
      xmlns=&amp;quot;http://www.language-archives.org/OLAC/1.0/&amp;quot;
      xmlns:xsi=&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance&amp;quot;
      xsi:schemaLocation=&amp;quot;http://www.language-archives.org/OLAC/1.0/
                 http://www.language-archives.org/OLAC/1.0/olac-archive.xsd&amp;quot;
      type=&amp;quot;institutional&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;archiveURL&amp;gt;http://www.ethnologue.com&amp;lt;/archiveURL&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;curator&amp;gt;Raymond G. Gordon, Jr.&amp;lt;/curator&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;curatorTitle&amp;gt;Ethnologue Editor&amp;lt;/curatorTitle&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;curatorEmail&amp;gt;mailto:editor_ethnologue@sil.org&amp;lt;/curatorEmail&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;institution&amp;gt;SIL International&amp;lt;/institution&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;institutionURL&amp;gt;http://www.sil.org&amp;lt;/institutionURL&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;shortLocation&amp;gt;Dallas, USA&amp;lt;/shortLocation&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;location&amp;gt;7500 W. Camp Wisdom Rd., Dallas, TX 75236, U.S.A.&amp;lt;/location&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;synopsis&amp;gt;The Ethnologue data provider gives a metadata record for every
   language entry in the Web edition of the Ethnologue.  The latter provides
   basic information about each of the 7,000+ modern language of the world
   (both living and recently extinct).&amp;lt;/synopsis&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;access&amp;gt;Every resource described by the Ethnologue data provider is a
   public Web page that may be accessed without restriction. Reuse of 
   material on the site is subject to the Terms of Use that are
   posted.&amp;lt;/access&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/olac-archive&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we see in the above example, the &lt;code&gt;olac-archive&lt;/code&gt; or OAI &lt;em&gt;repository&lt;/em&gt; is the Ethnologue. It is typed as an &lt;em&gt;institutional&lt;/em&gt; OLAC archive. However, is the Ethnologue actually a language archive? What language resource can you go to the archive and get? It seems to me to be more like a typological database about socio-linguistic topics. While it might be too late now to do anything about it, the OLAC schema could have used the XML element &lt;code&gt;olac-provider&lt;/code&gt; as a more neutral term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of the term &amp;ldquo;archive&amp;rdquo; to mean all data providers to OLAC is &lt;em&gt;confusing&lt;/em&gt; because the language of academic discourse around language archives and OLAC data providers is not discrete. That is, the language does not provide distinct categories where categories would be helpful. The OLAC protocol distinguishes between organizations and personal data providers, but OLAC doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any further distinction. Research which uses OLAC records as a dataset should take the diversity of data providers into account as analyses present observations and claims—especially about the description of artifacts, or percentages of Dublin Core Element use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the claims that all data providers are &amp;ldquo;archives&amp;rdquo; is &lt;em&gt;inaccurate&lt;/em&gt;—or careless at best. In my assessment I find that there is a mix of provider types which does not neatly fit into the &lt;code&gt;personal&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;institutional&lt;/code&gt; dichotomy. In part that is because the &lt;code&gt;personal&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;institutional&lt;/code&gt; dichotomy describes the &lt;em&gt;OAI Data provider&lt;/em&gt;, not the &lt;em&gt;OAI repository&lt;/em&gt;. As I evaluate the diversity of OAI repositories I find the dimension of &lt;code&gt;personal&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;institutional&lt;/code&gt; less useful than one which included the terms: &lt;em&gt;Archive, Repository, Museum, Gallery, Library, Special Collection, Personal Portfolio, Lab or Department Portfolio, Project Portfolio, Typological Database, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Bibliography&lt;/em&gt;. Roughly these fall into the broad categories of &lt;em&gt;access institutions&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;exhibits&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;reference resources&lt;/em&gt;. The following diagram puts these terms on a gradient of a data provider which is highly likely to have an advertised resource and be able to provide access to that resource to a provider which is likely not able to provide access to an advertised resource. It is this second dimension which is likely to impact the nature of OLAC records more than the first dimension of &lt;code&gt;personal&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;institutional&lt;/code&gt;. The second dimension should be considered when using OLAC records as an object of study. If OLAC were to revise its protocol, these other terms should be considered to provide a better context for evaluating the quality and completeness of the records.&lt;/p&gt;



  
  
  














&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-types-of-olac-data-providers&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/diversity-and-typology-across-olac-providers/Data_contributors_hu8da133b01ff086a7adb712d959fc9935_89197_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Types of OLAC Data Providers.&#34;&gt;

  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/post/diversity-and-typology-across-olac-providers/Data_contributors_hu8da133b01ff086a7adb712d959fc9935_89197_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;Types of OLAC Data Providers.&#34; width=&#34;2318&#34; height=&#34;840&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Types of OLAC Data Providers.
      
&lt;span class=&#34;img-attribution&#34;&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://hugh4.us&#34;&gt; Hugh Paterson III&lt;span itemprop=&#34;creator&#34; itemtype=&#34;https://schema.org/Person&#34; itemscope&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;name&#34; content=&#34;Hugh Paterson III&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- It is an interesting difference presented in this paper: http://www.language-archives.org/documents/community-providers.html were B&amp;S take the following approach to parsing (open language (archive community)).

[1]: Additional discussion on the OAI name terms can be found in slide 23 of the linked slide presentation: http://eprints.rclis.org/4586/1/tutorial3muller.pdf
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Awesome List for Open Source Software</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/an-awesome-list-for-open-source-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 14:14:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/an-awesome-list-for-open-source-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The world is full of problems. Some of these can be solved through the use of technology. Other problems can&amp;rsquo;t be solved directly through the use of technology, but the deployment of technologies can impact social environments and social interactions in a way so that the problems not solvable directly though technology can be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low-resource languages suffer from one of the problems of the second type. That is there is a sociological problem that follows briefly in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel-good, and do-good linguists often want to help &amp;ldquo;low-resourced&amp;rdquo; language community have digital tools in their language. This scenario is mirrored by the a different scenario, which may be contrasted with people &amp;ldquo;helping&amp;rdquo; from the outside. That is,people from within the low-resource language want to create tools for using their language - often in written form - in digital contexts. The result is that there are often a set of persons who are project managers, or who hold the business strings (access to grant funding, and are responsible for contracting with technologists to implement the project ideas and goals). The problem that occurs is that the more project managers there are (which might be more than one per language - with over 7,000 languages) the more divergent the technological solutions which are expensive and often not compatible or extensible - even if they are &amp;ldquo;open sourced&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problem we are trying to solve is the communication problem between the plethora of coders which vary from cowboy soloists to dedicated shops working on language software targeted for use in Low-resourced communities, and the growing number of visionary project managers, who might have a background in linguistics, but often not have one in information technology or in information technology project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of collaboration, and reusability of code are obvious. However, there still stand a large gap between the project manager and the coding technologist. We find that this gap can be characterized by two critical problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the things which have been coded - and for what purpose are they coded?
Assuming that this data can be gathered, how can this data be quirky made usable so that project managers can use the information intelligently in their evolving relationships with their technical teams? In summary we must create a pile of data, and then we need to make it usable.
In the spirit of taking baby steps, we have started to amass a pile of data (asking the question - what do we know has been coded), we have started with a solution which is more native to coders than to project managers. We have used an element of Github culture - &amp;lsquo;the Awesome list&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this does list does make a browse able list, it does not address the myriad of points of view which project managers come from. Synthesizing the data to match the various points of view; making the data relevant and usable is still an open task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
