<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hugh Paterson III &amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>U̠t-Ma&#39;in Lexicography</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-lexicography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-lexicography/</guid>
      <description>This project includes combining and collating several U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in databases that Becky Paterson has created over the 12 years she has worked with the U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in language community. We are also importing as many Hausa terms as possible for specific elicitation (such as regional plants and animals). The final database includes grammatical features of individual lexemes. We are including various external analyses from phonology tools. None of this data is currently public. But when it is, a link from here will be posted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U̠t-Ma&#39;in oral history</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-oral-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-utmatin-oral-history/</guid>
      <description>Becky received a grant to facilitate the collection of oral story data. The terms of the grant require her to record and archive oral histories of U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in speakers. My role in this project was to work with U̠t-Ma&amp;rsquo;in speakers (who actually did the recordings themselves) and present these to the Becky in way that she could arrange the files for archiving. In my role I got to visit around 40 different places in 7 different dialects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wasta Linux additions for the language scientist.</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-wasta-language-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-wasta-language-scientist/</guid>
      <description>I should make this image the wasta logo plus all the other logos I am using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Awesome list of Software for Endangered Languages</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2016-awesome-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2016-awesome-list/</guid>
      <description>Head over to Github everything is over there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linguistic Services Planning</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2015-linguistic-services-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2015-linguistic-services-planning/</guid>
      <description>This work was housed under SIL International&amp;rsquo;s Language Program Training (ILPT) department. I was able to help facilitate service design conversations both inside and outside the department. We used the business model canvas to capture business activities. We were then able to use the Value Proposition Canvas to talk about how we might add value to our customers by addressing their pain points. We wanted to know what a more valued service might look like to our customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIL Communications Strategy Consulting</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-sil-ils-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2017-sil-ils-communications/</guid>
      <description>This project is about creating a work environment where people are informed about the services and products that the organization is able to offer. It is about breaking down communication silos and working across corporate structures to create a unified workforce. I have the ongoing privilege of consulting with department heads and team leaders on interdepartmental communication and audience engagement strategies. Often this involves creative uses of technology and creating data management plans and publishing work flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The minority language typing experience</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-experience/</guid>
      <description>Previous work:
This project follows and builds upon the project where keyboard layouts for Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec were produced. This project uses data from Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec but purposely extends the scope of the analysis to include Latin and Cyrillic script languages, particularly focusing on those with diacritics which express tone.
Goals:
The goal of this project is to bring &amp;lsquo;natural&amp;rsquo;, intuitive, and easy to use typing experiences in the form of keyboard layout designs to minority language users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Experience Consulting on SIL.org</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2013-sil-org/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec Keyboards</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-mexico-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-mexico-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>This project formalized my interest in the text input problem. While doing text input for the Meꞌphaa language documentation project it was imperative to get Unicode encoded texts. I worked with Kevin Cline to create OS X and native Windows OS keyboards for Meꞌphaa writers. We used Ukelele to create the OS X keyboards and Microsoft Keyboard Layout Creator (MSKLC) to create the Windows keyboards.
Upon hearing of my new found skills, language users from the Sochiapam Chinantec community asked me to make an OS X keyboard for their language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-audio-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-audio-digitization/</guid>
      <description>This project involved the accession, cataloging and digitization of several collections. It also involved cataloging of multiple collections already accessioned but not yet cataloged. I was responsible for identifying and collecting metadata relevant for audio collections. I communicated with the SIL Language and Culture Archive staff when metadata schemas in place were insufficient for audio collections. I identified and recommended changes to metadata profiles used at the time by the Language and Culture Archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-photo-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-photo-digitization/</guid>
      <description>I served as project manager, recruiting and supervising a volunteer workforce. Together we cataloged and scanned over 1000 photos.
We also repatriated some photos. We took old photo albums to reunions where former SIL staff identified persons and places in the images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Digitization</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-text-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-americas-area-text-digitization/</guid>
      <description>I worked with the SIL Americas Area Access Coordinator to make language materials available to translators, researchers, and language development workers. There is a wealth of information that is simply inaccessible to those who could use it. I helped in the implementation of a system to make these materials available digitally, via the internet. Access to these materials affects the mechanics of language development and translation projects throughout the Americas Area and around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Grammarian of digital file names is the loneliest job of them all.
Corpus of descriptive work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdental approximant</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-interdental-approximant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 08:18:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2010-interdental-approximant/</guid>
      <description>This research project was spearheaded by Ken Olson. As a collaborator with him I focused on the Historical linguistics status of the interdental approximant in Philippine languages. I also did a lot of library resources discovery and acquisition.
In this project description I have listed more than my contribution because I am not sure there is anywhere else that has pulled together the combined research on this topic.
Results &amp;amp; Significance:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>