<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fieldwork | Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/fieldwork/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/fieldwork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Fieldwork</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Hugh Paterson III © 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 14:16:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/media/HughPaterson.jpg</url>
      <title>Fieldwork</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tag/fieldwork/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>InField</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/infield/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 14:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/post/infield/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working on describing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fieldworks.sil.org/flex/&#34; title=&#34;FLEx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FLEx&lt;/a&gt; software eco-system (for both a blog post and an info-graphic). In the process I googled 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22language&amp;#43;documentation%22&amp;#43;workflow%22&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Language documentation workflow&lt;/a&gt; and was promptly directed to resources created for InField and aggregated via &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20130715000000*/http://www.ctldc.org/&#34; title=&#34;Consortium on Training in Language Documentation and Conservation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ctldc.org&lt;/a&gt;. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctldc.org/clearing-house/item/65-principles-and-multimedia-tools-for-sustainable-language-documentation-maintenance-and-revitalization&#34;&gt;http://www.ctldc.org/clearing-house/item/65-principles-and-multimedia-tools-for-sustainable-language-documentation-maintenance-and-revitalization&lt;/a&gt; An amazing set of resources. the ctldc.org website is well put together and the content from 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20130117034354/http://logos.uoregon.edu/infield2010/workshops/tools-for-language/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;InField 2010&lt;/a&gt; and 2008 is amazing - I wish I could have been there. They incorporate new technologies and methods in ways that SIL fieldwork programs do not attempt to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that there is a very large student base for these kinds of summer schools (competency exchanges). Therefore, I am almost convinced that most SIL staff pursuing linguistic fieldwork should just go to InField&amp;hellip; To do that effectivly, SIL would need to provide teachers and content to these various summer training programs. It means that SIL would need to organize itself more modularly around the course, rather than around the course-set or program. On the other hand, it is true that InField seems to be targeted at someone who has had more than one semester of linguistics training. SIL schools seem to be constructed at taking someone with zero linguistic background.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa and Sochiapam Chinantec Keyboards</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-mexico-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2012-mexico-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project formalized my interest in the text input problem. While doing text input for the Meꞌphaa language documentation project it was imperative to get Unicode encoded texts. I worked with Kevin Cline to create OS X and native Windows OS keyboards for Meꞌphaa writers.  We used 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://scripts.sil.org/ukelele&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ukelele&lt;/a&gt; to create the OS X keyboards and  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170202084913/https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/globalization/keyboardlayouts.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microsoft Keyboard Layout Creator (MSKLC)&lt;/a&gt; to create the Windows keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon hearing of my new found skills, language users from the Sochiapam Chinantec community asked me to make an OS X keyboard for their language. In both cases existing keyboard layouts were matched to synchronize the user experience across the OSes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the design choices in the original layouts did not make sense to me. Hence the birth of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/Hugh-CV/project/2014-typing-expereince/&#34;&gt;The minority language typing experience&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meꞌphaa Language Documentation</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/project/2011-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I supported and conducted field work in this multi-scholar collaboration documenting the various speech varieties of the Meꞌphaa Genius. The protagonist in this effort was Dr. Steven Marlett. He applied for and was awarded&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; a DEL-NEH fellowship and invited Kevin an me to work on our own, but adjacent projects at the same place and time as he was working on his project. Contextually this was a very interesting project and formative in my scholarly experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My major contribution to the research project(s) was two fold: First, I provided audio and video recording technical expertise for the recording of communicative events; second, I provided file organization and metadata support for all the scholars involved. Contextually this role was very interesting because I functioned as a field archivist, and multi-media recording technician working with linguists. This pairing was not well understood, even by me, at the time. Commonly understood roles were &lt;em&gt;IT Support&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;linguist&lt;/em&gt;, I fit neither 100%. Therefore, I sometimes say that &amp;ldquo;being a grammarian of digital file names is the loneliest job of them all&amp;rdquo;. However, if social expectations among team members can be well established, including a &lt;em&gt;field archivist&lt;/em&gt; on an interdisciplinary linguistic team may provide significant advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Dr. Steven Marlett&amp;rsquo;s Fellowship lasted 12 months, my own involvement consisted of two discontinuous three-month stents. Many of the lessons learned and reflections on our project are recorded in short (or longer) blog posts. Significant though are that 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.und.edu/theses/1410&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kevin Cline used this time to gather data for a successfully defended Masters Thesis&lt;/a&gt;, Dr. Marlett would use the knowledge and relationships to write a massive amount of descriptive material and texts on the Meꞌphaa speech varieties. These are known as the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mexico.sil.org/publications/i-wpindex/work_papers_-_mephaa_grammar_files&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meꞌphaa Grammar Files&lt;/a&gt; and are published under the SIL Mexico Working Papers series. My own scholarly contribution informed by and influenced through this project would span multiple topics but would include the areas of text input, metadata schemas, project managment, and geo-linguistics (language maps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;File-man.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hugh in recording&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20111110085938/http://www.neh.gov/grants/guidelines/pdf/DEL_NEH_Marlett.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marlett Fellowship Narrative&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- http://www.neh.gov/grants/guidelines/pdf/DEL_NEH_Marlett.pdf --&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
