<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Phonetic Alphabet on Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tags/international-phonetic-alphabet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Phonetic Alphabet on Hugh&#39;s Curriculum Vitae</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hugh Paterson III &amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/tags/international-phonetic-alphabet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-icphs-tone-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/talk/2015-icphs-tone-presentation/</guid>
      <description>This was a poster presentation of the full published paper mentioned here.
Citeable as
Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA. Poser presentation at ICPhS 2015. 18th International Conference of Phonetic Sciences. University of Glasgow: Glasgow, UK.
Though you should probably just cite the paper which is citeable as:
Hugh J. Paterson III (2015) Phonetic transcription of tone in the IPA. In The Scottish Consortium for ICPhS 2015 (Ed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The phonetic status of the (inter)dental approximant.</title>
      <link>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2010-interdental/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hughandbecky.us/Hugh-CV/publication/2010-interdental/</guid>
      <description>Citeable as:
Kenneth S. Olson, Jeff Mielke, Josephine Sanicas-Daguman, Carol Jean Pebley and Hugh J. Paterson (2010) The phonetic status of the (inter)dental approximant. Journal of the International Phonetic Association, 40.2 , pp. 199-215. doi:10.1017/S0025100309990296
Comments: My contribution in this collective work involved extensive library research, the collection of sources, translation of sources, and evaluating the personal un-published field notes of previous scholars. Encouraged in the historical comparative work by Ken Olson, I suggest that there is enough evidence to support the idea that the interdental approximant is a retention, rather than independent innovations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>